<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<!-- maintainer-needed -->
	<longdescription lang="en">
		This is sieve-connect. A client for the ManageSieve protocol,
		as specifed in RFC 5804. Historically, this was MANAGESIEVE as
		implemented by timsieved in Cyrus IMAP. This software is licensed
		and the terms are provided in the file "LICENSE" as supplied
		with this software (BSD license without the advertising clause).

		SIEVE is an RFC-specified language for mail filtering, which at
		time of writing is specified in a list of RFCs at the end of this
		document, plus various drafts, both IETF and individual submissions.
		It's designed to be regular enough for machines to be able to
		manipulate, whilst still being editable by humans. Alas, not many
		clients actually implement this instead of embedding their own
		internal codes in sieve comments, defeating the goal of being able
		to edit with a client of your choice.

		This is not yet fully compatible with RFC 5804, but is moving
		towards that from the timsieved baseline; some issues to be
		worked on are documented in the "TODO" file.

		sieve-connect speaks ManageSieve and supports TLS for connection
		privacy and also authentication if using client certificates.
		sieve-connect will use SASL authentication; SASL integrity layers
		are not supported, use TLS instead. GSSAPI-based authentication
		should generally work, provided that client and server can use a
		common underlaying protocol. If it doesn't work for you, please
		report the issue.

		sieve-connect is designed to be both a tool which can be invoked
		from scripts and also a decent interactive client. It should also
		be a drop-in replacement for "sieveshell", as supplied with Cyrus
		IMAP.
	</longdescription>
	<upstream>
		<bugs-to>https://github.com/syscomet/sieve-connect/issues</bugs-to>
		<remote-id type="github">syscomet/sieve-connect</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
