<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer type="person">
    <name>Arsen Arsenović</name>
    <email>arsen@gentoo.org</email>
  </maintainer>
  <upstream>
    <remote-id type="github">be5invis/iosevka</remote-id>
  </upstream>
  <use>
    <flag name="iosevka">
      Install the classic Iosevka font.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-slab">
      Install Iosevka Slab, a monospace slab-serif font.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-curly">
      Install Iosevka Curly, a curlier variant of Iosevka.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-curly-slab">
      Install Iosevka Curly Slab, the curly font, with slab-serifs.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss01">
      Install Iosevka SS01, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Andale Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss02">
      Install Iosevka SS02, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Anonymous Pro Style.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss03">
      Install Iosevka SS03, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Consolas.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss04">
      Install Iosevka SS04, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Menlo.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss05">
      Install Iosevka SS05, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Fira Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss06">
      Install Iosevka SS06, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Liberation Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss07">
      Install Iosevka SS07, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Monaco.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss08">
      Install Iosevka SS08, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Pragmata Pro.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss09">
      Install Iosevka SS09, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Source Code Pro.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss10">
      Install Iosevka SS10, an Iosevka variant made in the style of Envy
      Code R.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss11">
      Install Iosevka SS11, an Iosevka variant made in the style of X
      Windows Fixed.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss12">
      Install Iosevka SS12, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Ubuntu Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss13">
      Install Iosevka SS13, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Lucida.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss14">
      Install Iosevka SS14, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      JetBrains Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss15">
      Install Iosevka SS15, an Iosevka variant made in the style of IBM
      Plex Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss16">
      Install Iosevka SS16, an Iosevka variant made in the style of PT
      Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss17">
      Install Iosevka SS17, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Recursive Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-ss18">
      Install Iosevka SS18, an Iosevka variant made in the style of
      Input Mono.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-aile">
      Install Iosevka Aile, a quasi-proportional sans-serif font.
    </flag>
    <flag name="iosevka-etoile">
      Install Iosevka Etoile, a quasi-proportional slab-serif font.
    </flag>
  </use>
</pkgmetadata>
