<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="project">
		<email>chromium@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Chromium in Gentoo Project</name>
	</maintainer>
	<use>
		<flag name="js-type-check">Enable JavaScript type-checking for Chrome's web technology-based UI. Requires Java.</flag>
		<flag name="component-build">Split build into more shared libraries to speed up linking. Mostly intended for debugging and development, NOT RECOMMENDED for general use.</flag>
		<flag name="debug">Enable DCHECK feature with severity configurable at runtime. Mostly intended for debugging and development, NOT RECOMMENDED for general use.</flag>
		<flag name="gtk4">Build with GTK4 headers.</flag>
		<flag name="headless">Build Ozone only with headless backend, NOT RECOMMENDED for general use.</flag>
		<flag name="hangouts">Enable support for Google Hangouts features such as screen sharing</flag>
		<flag name="libcxx">Use bundled libc++ instead of libstdc++ for building.</flag>
		<flag name="lto">Build with Link Time Optimizations (via clang's ThinLTO)</flag>
		<flag name="official">Enable Official build instead of Developer build.</flag>
		<flag name="pic">Disable optimized assembly code that is not PIC friendly</flag>
		<flag name="proprietary-codecs">Enable codecs for patent-encumbered audio and video formats.</flag>
		<flag name="screencast">Enable support for remote desktop and screen cast using <pkg>media-video/pipewire</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="suid">Build the SUID sandbox, which is only needed on CONFIG_USER_NS=n kernels</flag>
		<flag name="system-ffmpeg">Use system ffmpeg instead of the bundled one</flag>
		<flag name="system-harfbuzz">Use system harfbuzz instead of the bundled one.</flag>
		<flag name="system-icu">Use system icu instead of the bundled one</flag>
		<flag name="system-png">Use system libpng instead of the bundled one.</flag>
		<flag name="widevine">Unsupported closed-source DRM capability (required by Netflix VOD)</flag>
	</use>
</pkgmetadata>
