<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<herd>proxy-maintainers</herd>
	<maintainer>
		<email>idl0r@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Christian Ruppert</name>
	</maintainer>
	<maintainer>
		<email>peter@stuge.se</email>
		<description>Please CC on all bugs</description>
	</maintainer>
	<use>
		<flag name="atahpt">Highpoint (HPT) ATA/RAID controller support</flag>
		<flag name="atavia">Support for VIA VT6421A SATA controllers</flag>
		<flag name="bitbang_spi">Bitbanging SPI infrastructure</flag>
		<flag name="buspirate_spi">Enable Bus Pirate SPI programmer</flag>
		<flag name="dediprog">Dediprog SF100 support</flag>
		<flag name="drkaiser">Enable Dr. Kaiser programmer</flag>
		<flag name="dummy">Enable dummy tracing</flag>
		<flag name="ft2232_spi">Enable ftdi programmer, flashing through FTDI/SPI USB interface</flag>
		<flag name="gfxnvidia">Enable NVIDIA programmer</flag>
		<flag name="internal">Enable internal/onboard support</flag>
		<flag name="internal_dmi">Enable internal DMI decoding rather than use <pkg>sys-apps/dmidecode</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="it8212">Support for ITE IT8212F ATA/RAID controllers</flag>
		<flag name="linux_spi">Enable support for Linux userspace spidev interface</flag>
		<flag name="mstarddc_spi">Support for SPI flash ROMs accessible through DDC in MSTAR-equipped displays</flag>
		<flag name="nic3com">Enable 3Com NIC programmer</flag>
		<flag name="nicintel">Support for Intel NICs</flag>
		<flag name="nicintel_eeprom">Support for EEPROMs on Intel Gigabit network cards</flag>
		<flag name="nicintel_spi">Support for SPI on Intel NICs</flag>
		<flag name="nicnatsemi">Support for National Semiconductor NICs</flag>
		<flag name="nicrealtek">Support for Realtek NICs</flag>
		<flag name="ogp_spi">Enable support for OGP (Open Graphics Project) SPI flashing</flag>
		<flag name="pickit2_spi">SUpport for SPI flash ROMs accessible via Microchip PICkit2</flag>
		<flag name="pony_spi">Enable support for SI-Prog like hardware by Lancos</flag>
		<flag name="rayer_spi">RayeR SPIPGM hardware support</flag>
		<flag name="satasii">Enable programmer for SiI SATA controllers</flag>
		<flag name="satamv">Enable programmer for Marvell SATA controllers</flag>
		<flag name="serprog">Enable Serial Flasher programmer</flag>
		<flag name="tools">Install additional tools</flag>
		<flag name="usbblaster">Enable support for Altera USB-Blaster dongles</flag>
		<flag name="usbblaster_spi">Enable support for Altera USB-Blaster dongles</flag>
		<flag name="wiki">Enable wiki informations, like supported devices etc.</flag>
	</use>
	<longdescription lang="en">
flashrom is a utility for identifying, reading, writing, verifying and erasing flash chips. It is designed to flash BIOS/EFI/coreboot/firmware/optionROM images on mainboards, network/graphics/storage controller cards, and various other programmer devices.

    Supports more than 380 flash chips, 260 chipsets, 450 mainboards, 50 PCI devices, 12 USB devices and various parallel/serial port-based programmers.
    Supports parallel, LPC, FWH and SPI flash interfaces and various chip packages (DIP32, PLCC32, DIP8, SO8/SOIC8, TSOP32, TSOP40, TSOP48, BGA and more)
    No physical access needed, root access is sufficient (not needed for some programmers).
    No bootable floppy disk, bootable CD-ROM or other media needed.
    No keyboard or monitor needed. Simply reflash remotely via SSH.
    No instant reboot needed. Reflash your chip in a running system, verify it, be happy. The new firmware will be present next time you boot.
    Crossflashing and hotflashing is possible as long as the flash chips are electrically and logically compatible (same protocol). Great for recovery.
    Scriptability. Reflash a whole pool of identical machines at the same time from the command line. It is recommended to check flashrom output and error codes.
    Speed. flashrom is often much faster than most vendor flash tools.
    Portability. Supports DOS, Linux, FreeBSD, NetBSD, OpenBSD, DragonFly BSD, Solaris, Mac OS X, and other Unix-like OSes. Partial Windows support is available (no internal programmer support at the moment, hence no "BIOS flashing").
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
