<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>christian.tietz@mailbox.org</email>
		<name>Christian Tietz</name>
	</maintainer>
	<maintainer type="project">
		<email>proxy-maint@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Proxy Maintainers</name>
	</maintainer>
	<maintainer type="project">
		<email>xfce@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>XFCE Team</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription lang="en">
		Whisker Menu is an alternate application launcher for Xfce.
		When you open it you are shown a list of applications you have
		marked as favorites. You can browse through all of your installed
		applications by clicking on the category buttons on the side.
		Top level categories make browsing fast, and simple to switch
		between. Additionally, Whisker Menu keeps a list of the last
		ten applications that you’ve launched from it.

		Favorites are easy to add and reorder. When browsing through
		your applications, right-click on any of them and select “Add
		to Favorites”. Simply drag and drop your favorites list to
		arrange them to suit your needs. You can remove them at any
		time from another right-click option.

		If you’re not sure exactly where a program is listed, instead
		of browsing through each category you can simply enter a search
		term. The search field is focused when opening the menu, so you
		can just start typing. Application descriptions as well as names
		are searched, which allows you to find a program by using a
		general word (such as “browser” to find all web browsers
		installed on your computer).
	</longdescription>
	<upstream>
		<maintainer status="active">
			<email>graeme@gottcode.org</email>
			<name>Graeme Gott</name>
		</maintainer>
		<bugs-to>https://github.com/gottcode/xfce4-whiskermenu-plugin/issues?labels=bug&amp;state=open</bugs-to>
		<changelog>https://gottcode.org/xfce4-whiskermenu-plugin/#releasenotes</changelog>
		<remote-id type="github">gottcode/xfce4-whiskermenu-plugin</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
