<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200804-21">
  <title>Adobe Flash Player: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been identified, the worst of which allow
    arbitrary code execution on a user's system via a malicious Flash file.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">adobe-flash</product>
  <announced>2008-04-18</announced>
  <revised>2009-05-28: 02</revised>
  <bug>204344</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="www-plugins/adobe-flash" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">9.0.124.0</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">9.0.124.0</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    The Adobe Flash Player is a renderer for the popular SWF file format,
    which is commonly used to provide interactive websites, digital
    experiences and mobile content.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in Adobe Flash:
    </p>
    <ul>
    <li>
    Secunia Research and Zero Day Initiative reported a boundary error
    related to DeclareFunction2 Actionscript tags in SWF files
    (CVE-2007-6019).
    </li>
    <li>
    The ISS X-Force and the Zero Day Initiative reported an unspecified
    input validation error that might lead to a buffer overflow
    (CVE-2007-0071).
    </li>
    <li>
    Microsoft, UBsecure and JPCERT/CC reported that cross-domain policy
    files are not checked before sending HTTP headers to another domain
    (CVE-2008-1654) and that it does not sufficiently restrict the
    interpretation and usage of cross-domain policy files (CVE-2007-6243).
    </li>
    <li>
    The Stanford University and Ernst and Young's Advanced Security Center
    reported that Flash does not pin DNS hostnames to a single IP
    addresses, allowing for DNS rebinding attacks (CVE-2007-5275,
    CVE-2008-1655).
    </li>
    <li>
    The Google Security Team and Minded Security Multiple reported multiple
    cross-site scripting vulnerabilities when passing input to Flash
    functions (CVE-2007-6637).
    </li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote attacker could entice a user to open a specially crafted file
    (usually in a web browser), possibly leading to the execution of
    arbitrary code with the privileges of the user running the Adobe Flash
    Player. The attacker could also cause a user's machine to send HTTP
    requests to other hosts, establish TCP sessions with arbitrary hosts,
    bypass the security sandbox model, or conduct Cross-Site Scripting and
    Cross-Site Request Forgery attacks.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Adobe Flash Player users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=www-plugins/adobe-flash-9.0.124.0"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-0071">CVE-2007-0071</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-5275">CVE-2007-5275</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6019">CVE-2007-6019</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6243">CVE-2007-6243</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6637">CVE-2007-6637</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-1654">CVE-2008-1654</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-1655">CVE-2008-1655</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2008-04-17T10:39:32Z">
    vorlon
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2008-04-18T01:16:42Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2008-04-18T01:18:41Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
</glsa>
