<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200407-22">
  <title>phpMyAdmin: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities in phpMyAdmin may allow a remote attacker with a
    valid user account to alter configuration variables and execute arbitrary
    PHP code.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">dev-db/phpmyadmin</product>
  <announced>2004-07-29</announced>
  <revised count="02">2006-05-22</revised>
  <bug>57890</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="dev-db/phpmyadmin" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">2.5.7_p1</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">2.5.7</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    phpMyAdmin is a popular, web-based MySQL administration tool written in
    PHP. It allows users to administer a MySQL database from a web-browser.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Two serious vulnerabilities exist in phpMyAdmin. The first allows any
    user to alter the server configuration variables (including host, name,
    and password) by appending new settings to the array variables that
    hold the configuration in a GET statement. The second allows users to
    include arbitrary PHP code to be executed within an eval() statement in
    table name configuration settings. This second vulnerability is only
    exploitable if $cfg['LeftFrameLight'] is set to FALSE.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    Authenticated users can alter configuration variables for their running
    copy of phpMyAdmin. The impact of this should be minimal. However, the
    second vulnerability would allow an authenticated user to execute
    arbitrary PHP code with the permissions of the webserver, potentially
    allowing a serious Denial of Service or further remote compromise.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    The second, more serious vulnerability is only exploitable if
    $cfg['LeftFrameLight'] is set to FALSE. In the default Gentoo
    installation, this is set to TRUE. There is no known workaround for the
    first.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All phpMyAdmin users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    
    # emerge -pv "&gt;=dev-db/phpmyadmin-2.5.7_p1"
    # emerge "&gt;=dev-db/phpmyadmin-2.5.7_p1"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://www.securityfocus.com/archive/1/367486">BugTraq Announcement</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-2631">CVE-2004-2631</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-2632">CVE-2004-2632</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester">
    koon
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    dmargoli
  </metadata>
</glsa>
