<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200405-24">
  <title>MPlayer, xine-lib: vulnerabilities in RTSP stream handling</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities, including remotely exploitable buffer overflows,
    have been found in code common to MPlayer and the xine library.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">mplayer</product>
  <announced>2004-05-28</announced>
  <revised count="01">2004-05-28</revised>
  <bug>49387</bug>
  <access>remote </access>
  <affected>
    <package name="media-video/mplayer" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.0_pre4</unaffected>
      <unaffected range="le">0.92-r1</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">1.0_pre4</vulnerable>
    </package>
    <package name="media-libs/xine-lib" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1_rc4</unaffected>
      <unaffected range="le">0.9.13-r3</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">1_rc4</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    MPlayer is a movie player capable of handling multiple multimedia file
    formats. xine-lib is a multimedia player library used by several graphical
    user interfaces, including xine-ui. They both use the same code to handle
    Real-Time Streaming Protocol (RTSP) streams from RealNetworks servers.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been found and fixed in the RTSP handling
    code common to recent versions of these two packages. These vulnerabilities
    include several remotely exploitable buffer overflows.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    A remote attacker, posing as a RTSP stream server, can execute arbitrary
    code with the rights of the user of the software playing the stream
    (MPlayer or any player using xine-lib). Another attacker may entice a user
    to use a maliciously crafted URL or playlist to achieve the same results.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    For MPlayer, there is no known workaround at this time. For xine-lib, you
    can delete the xineplug_inp_rtsp.so file.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users should upgrade to non-vulnerable versions of MPlayer and
    xine-lib:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv "&gt;=media-video/mplayer-1.0_pre4"
    # emerge "&gt;=media-video/mplayer-1.0_pre4"

    # emerge -pv "&gt;=media-libs/xine-lib-1_rc4"
    # emerge "&gt;=media-libs/xine-lib-1_rc4"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://xinehq.de/index.php/security/XSA-2004-3">Xine security advisory</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0433">CAN-2004-0433</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    koon
  </metadata>
</glsa>
