<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200904-17">
  <title>Adobe Reader: User-assisted execution of arbitrary code</title>
  <synopsis>
    Adobe Reader is vulnerable to execution of arbitrary code.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">acroread</product>
  <announced>2009-04-18</announced>
  <revised>2009-04-18: 01</revised>
  <bug>259992</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-text/acroread" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">8.1.4</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">8.1.4</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Adobe Reader (formerly Adobe Acrobat Reader) is a closed-source PDF
    reader.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in Adobe Reader:
    </p>
    <ul>
    <li>
    Alin Rad Pop of Secunia Research reported a heap-based buffer overflow
    when processing PDF files containing a malformed JBIG2 symbol
    dictionary segment (CVE-2009-0193).
    </li>
    <li>
    A buffer overflow related to a non-JavaScript function call and
    possibly an embedded JBIG2 image stream has been reported
    (CVE-2009-0658).
    </li>
    <li>
    Tenable Network Security reported a stack-based buffer overflow that
    can be triggered via a crafted argument to the getIcon() method of a
    Collab object (CVE-2009-0927).
    </li>
    <li>
    Sean Larsson of iDefense Labs reported a heap-based buffer overflow
    when processing a PDF file containing a JBIG2 stream with a size
    inconsistency related to an unspecified table (CVE-2009-0928).
    </li>
    <li>
    Jonathan Brossard of the iViZ Security Research Team reported an
    unspecified vulnerability related to JBIG2 and input validation
    (CVE-2009-1061).
    </li>
    <li>
    Will Dormann of CERT/CC reported a vulnerability lading to memory
    corruption related to JBIG2 (CVE-2009-1062).
    </li>
    </ul> <p>
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote attacker could entice a user to open a specially crafted PDF
    document, possibly leading to the execution of arbitrary code with the
    privileges of the user running the application, or a Denial of Service.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Adobe Reader users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=app-text/acroread-8.1.4"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0193">CVE-2009-0193</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0658">CVE-2009-0658</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0927">CVE-2009-0927</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0928">CVE-2009-0928</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1061">CVE-2009-1061</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1062">CVE-2009-1062</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2009-04-14T12:25:56Z">
    keytoaster
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2009-04-16T22:30:05Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2009-04-16T22:30:15Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
</glsa>
