<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200403-07">
  <title>Multiple remote overflows and vulnerabilities in Ethereal</title>
  <synopsis>
    Mulitple overflows and vulnerabilities exist in Ethereal which may allow an
    attacker to crash the program or run arbitrary code.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">ethereal</product>
  <announced>2004-03-28</announced>
  <revised>2004-03-28: 01</revised>
  <bug>45543</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-analyzer/ethereal" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.10.3</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">0.10.2</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Quote from http://www.ethereal.com
    </p>
    <p>
    "Ethereal is used by network professionals around the world for
    troubleshooting, analysis, software and protocol development, and
    education. It has all of the standard features you would expect in a
    protocol analyzer, and several features not seen in any other product. Its
    open source license allows talented experts in the networking community to
    add enhancements. It runs on all popular computing platforms, including
    Unix, Linux, and Windows."
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>There are multiple vulnerabilities in versions of Ethereal earlier than 0.10.3, including:</p>
    <ul>
	<li>Thirteen buffer overflows in the following protocol dissectors: NetFlow, IGAP, EIGRP, PGM, IrDA, BGP, ISUP, and TCAP.</li>
      	<li>A zero-length Presentation protocol selector could make Ethereal crash.</li>
     	<li>A vulnerability in the RADIUS packet dissector which may crash ethereal.</li>
      	<li>A corrupt color filter file could cause a segmentation fault.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    These vulnerabilities may cause Ethereal to crash or may allow an attacker
    to run arbitrary code on the user's computer.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    While a workaround is not currently known for this issue, all users are
    advised to upgrade to the latest version of the affected package.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users should upgrade to the current version of the affected package:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    
    # emerge -pv "&gt;=net-analyzer/ethereal-0.10.3"
    # emerge "&gt;=net-analyzer/ethereal-0.10.3"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://www.ethereal.com/appnotes/enpa-sa-00013.html">Multiple security problems in Ethereal 0.10.2</uri>
    <uri link="https://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0176">CAN-2004-0176</uri>
    <uri link="https://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0365">CAN-2004-0365</uri>
    <uri link="https://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0367">CAN-2004-0367</uri>
  </references>
</glsa>
