<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="201703-04">
  <title>cURL: Certificate validation error</title>
  <synopsis>A coding error has been found in cURL, causing the TLS Certificate
    Status Request extension check to always return true.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">curl</product>
  <announced>2017-03-28</announced>
  <revised count="1">2017-03-28</revised>
  <bug>610572</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-misc/curl" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">7.53.0</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">7.53.0</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>cURL is a tool and libcurl is a library for transferring data with URL
      syntax.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>cURL and applications linked against libcurl support “OCSP
      stapling”, also known as the TLS Certificate Status Request extension
      (using the CURLOPT_SSL_VERIFYSTATUS option). When telling cURL to use
      this feature, it uses that TLS extension to ask for a fresh proof of the
      server’s certificate’s validity. If the server doesn’t support the
      extension, or fails to provide said proof, cURL is expected to return an
      error.
      Due to a coding mistake, the code that checks for a test success or
      failure, ends up always thinking there’s valid proof, even when there
      is none or if the server doesn’t support the TLS extension in question.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>Due to the error, a user maybe does not detect when a server’s
      certificate goes invalid or otherwise be mislead that the server is in a
      better shape than it is in reality.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>There is no known workaround at this time.</p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>All cURL users should upgrade to the latest version:</p>
    
    <code>
      # emerge --sync
      # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=net-misc/curl-7.53.0"
    </code>
    
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://nvd.nist.gov/nvd.cfm?cvename=CVE-2017-2629">CVE-2017-2629</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2017-03-07T21:41:04Z">BlueKnight</metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2017-03-28T01:57:09Z">whissi</metadata>
</glsa>
