<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200801-07">
  <title>Adobe Flash Player: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been identified, the worst of which allow
    arbitrary code execution on a user's system via a malicious Flash file.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">adobe-flash</product>
  <announced>2008-01-20</announced>
  <revised>2009-05-28: 03</revised>
  <bug>193519</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="www-plugins/adobe-flash" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">9.0.115.0</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">9.0.115.0</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    The Adobe Flash Player is a renderer for the popular SWF file format,
    which is commonly used to provide interactive websites, digital
    experiences and mobile content.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <ul>
    <li>Flash contains a copy of PCRE which is vulnerable to a heap-based
    buffer overflow (GLSA 200711-30, CVE-2007-4768).</li>
    <li>Aaron Portnoy reported an unspecified vulnerability related to
    input validation (CVE-2007-6242).</li>
    <li>Jesse Michael and Thomas Biege reported that Flash does not
    correctly set memory permissions (CVE-2007-6246).</li>
    <li>Dan Boneh, Adam Barth, Andrew Bortz, Collin Jackson, and Weidong
    Shao reported that Flash does not pin DNS hostnames to a single IP
    addresses, allowing for DNS rebinding attacks (CVE-2007-5275).</li>
    <li>David Neu reported an error withing the implementation of the
    Socket and XMLSocket ActionScript 3 classes (CVE-2007-4324).</li>
    <li>Toshiharu Sugiyama reported that Flash does not sufficiently
    restrict the interpretation and usage of cross-domain policy files,
    allowing for easier cross-site scripting attacks (CVE-2007-6243).</li>
    <li>Rich Cannings reported a cross-site scripting vulnerability in the
    way the "asfunction:" protocol was handled (CVE-2007-6244).</li>
    <li>Toshiharu Sugiyama discovered that Flash allows remote attackers to
    modify HTTP headers for client requests and conduct HTTP Request
    Splitting attacks (CVE-2007-6245).</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote attacker could entice a user to open a specially crafted file
    (usually in a web browser), possibly leading to the execution of
    arbitrary code with the privileges of the user running the Adobe Flash
    Player. The attacker could also cause a user's machine to establish TCP
    sessions with arbitrary hosts, bypass the Security Sandbox Model,
    obtain sensitive information, port scan arbitrary hosts, or conduct
    cross-site-scripting attacks.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Adobe Flash Player users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=www-plugins/adobe-flash-9.0.115.0"</code>
    <p>
    Please be advised that unaffected packages of the Adobe Flash Player
    have known problems when used from within the Konqueror and Opera
    browsers.
    </p>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-4324">CVE-2007-4324</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-4768">CVE-2007-4768</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-5275">CVE-2007-5275</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6242">CVE-2007-6242</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6243">CVE-2007-6243</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6244">CVE-2007-6244</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6245">CVE-2007-6245</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6246">CVE-2007-6246</uri>
    <uri link="https://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200711-30.xml">GLSA 200711-30</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2008-01-01T22:05:12Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2008-01-15T17:34:55Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2008-01-15T17:41:04Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
</glsa>
