<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200401-04">
  <title>GAIM 0.75 Remote overflows</title>
  <synopsis>
    Various overflows in the handling of AIM DirectIM packets was revealed in
    GAIM that could lead to a remote compromise of the IM client.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">GAIM</product>
  <announced>2004-01-26</announced>
  <revised count="01">2004-01-26</revised>
  <bug>39470</bug>
  <access>man-in-the-middle</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-im/gaim" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.75-r7</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">0.75-r7</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Gaim is a multi-platform and multi-protocol instant messaging
    client.  It is compatible with AIM , ICQ, MSN Messenger, Yahoo,
    IRC, Jabber, Gadu-Gadu, and the Zephyr networks.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Yahoo changed the authentication methods to their IM servers,
    rendering GAIM useless. The GAIM team released a rushed release
    solving this issue, however, at the same time a code audit
    revealed 12 new vulnerabilities.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    Due to the nature of instant messaging many of these bugs require
    man-in-the-middle attacks between the client and the server. But
    the underlying protocols are easy to implement and attacking
    ordinary TCP sessions is a fairly simple task. As a result, all
    users are advised to upgrade their GAIM installation.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        Users of GAIM 0.74 or below are affected by 7 of the
        vulnerabilities and are encouraged to upgrade.
      </li>
      <li>
        Users of GAIM 0.75 are affected by 11 of the vulnerabilities
        and are encouraged to upgrade to the patched version of GAIM
        offered by Gentoo.
      </li>
      <li>
        Users of GAIM 0.75-r6 are only affected by
        4 of the vulnerabilities, but are still urged to upgrade to
        maintain security.
      </li>
    </ul>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no immediate workaround; a software upgrade is required.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users are recommended to upgrade GAIM to 0.75-r7.
    </p>
    <code>
    $&gt; emerge sync
    $&gt; emerge -pv "&gt;=net-im/gaim-0.75-r7"
    $&gt; emerge "&gt;=net-im/gaim-0.75-r7"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://www.securityfocus.com/archive/1/351235/2004-01-23/2004-01-29/0">Security advisory from Stefan Esser</uri>
  </references>
</glsa>
