<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200407-03">
  <title>Apache 2: Remote denial of service attack</title>
  <synopsis>
    A bug in Apache may allow a remote attacker to perform a Denial of Service
    attack. With certain configurations this could lead to a heap based buffer
    overflow.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">Apache</product>
  <announced>2004-07-04</announced>
  <revised>2007-12-30: 02</revised>
  <bug>55441</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="www-servers/apache" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">2.0.49-r4</unaffected>
      <unaffected range="lt">2</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">2.0.49-r3</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    The Apache HTTP Server Project is an effort to develop and maintain an
    open-source HTTP server for modern operating systems. The goal of this
    project is to provide a secure, efficient and extensible server that
    provides services in tune with the current HTTP standards.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    A bug in the protocol.c file handling header lines will cause Apache to
    allocate memory for header lines starting with TAB or SPACE.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    An attacker can exploit this vulnerability to perform a Denial of Service
    attack by causing Apache to exhaust all memory. On 64 bit systems with more
    than 4GB of virtual memory a possible integer signedness error could lead
    to a buffer based overflow causing Apache to crash and under some
    circumstances execute arbitrary code as the user running Apache, usually
    "apache".
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time. All users are encouraged to
    upgrade to the latest available version:
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    Apache 2 users should upgrade to the latest version of Apache:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv "&gt;=www-servers/apache-2.0.49-r4"
    # emerge "&gt;=www-servers/apache-2.0.49-r4"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://www.guninski.com/httpd1.html">Georgi Guninski security advisory #70, 2004</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0493">CAN-2004-0493</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    jaervosz
  </metadata>
</glsa>
