<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200903-23">
  <title>Adobe Flash Player: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been identified, the worst of which allow
    arbitrary code execution on a user's system via a malicious Flash file.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">adobe-flash</product>
  <announced>2009-03-10</announced>
  <revised>2009-05-28: 04</revised>
  <bug>239543</bug>
  <bug>251496</bug>
  <bug>260264</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="www-plugins/adobe-flash" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">10.0.22.87</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">10.0.22.87</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    The Adobe Flash Player is a renderer for the popular SWF file format,
    which is commonly used to provide interactive websites, digital
    experiences and mobile content.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in Adobe Flash Player:
    </p>
    <ul>
    <li>The access scope of SystemsetClipboard() allows ActionScript
    programs to execute the method without user interaction
    (CVE-2008-3873).</li>
    <li>The access scope of FileReference.browse() and
    FileReference.download() allows ActionScript programs to execute the
    methods without user interaction (CVE-2008-4401).</li>
    <li>The Settings Manager controls can be disguised as normal graphical
    elements. This so-called "clickjacking" vulnerability was disclosed by
    Robert Hansen of SecTheory, Jeremiah Grossman of WhiteHat Security,
    Eduardo Vela, Matthew Mastracci of DotSpots, and Liu Die Yu of
    TopsecTianRongXin (CVE-2008-4503).</li>
    <li>Adan Barth (UC Berkely) and Collin Jackson (Stanford University)
    discovered a flaw occurring when interpreting HTTP response headers
    (CVE-2008-4818).</li>
    <li>Nathan McFeters and Rob Carter of Ernst and Young's Advanced
    Security Center are credited for finding an unspecified vulnerability
    facilitating DNS rebinding attacks (CVE-2008-4819).</li>
    <li>When used in a Mozilla browser, Adobe Flash Player does not
    properly interpret jar: URLs, according to a report by Gregory
    Fleischer of pseudo-flaw.net (CVE-2008-4821).</li>
    <li>Alex "kuza55" K. reported that Adobe Flash Player does not properly
    interpret policy files (CVE-2008-4822).</li>
    <li>The vendor credits Stefano Di Paola of Minded Security for
    reporting that an ActionScript attribute is not interpreted properly
    (CVE-2008-4823).</li>
    <li>Riley Hassell and Josh Zelonis of iSEC Partners reported multiple
    input validation errors (CVE-2008-4824).</li>
    <li>The aforementioned researchers also reported that ActionScript 2
    does not verify a member element's size when performing several known
    and other unspecified actions, that DefineConstantPool accepts an
    untrusted input value for a "constant count" and that character
    elements are not validated when retrieved from a data structure,
    possibly resulting in a null-pointer dereference (CVE-2008-5361,
    CVE-2008-5362, CVE-2008-5363).</li>
    <li>The vendor reported an unspecified arbitrary code execution
    vulnerability (CVE-2008-5499).</li>
    <li>Liu Die Yu of TopsecTianRongXin reported an unspecified flaw in the
    Settings Manager related to "clickjacking" (CVE-2009-0114).</li>
    <li>The vendor credits Roee Hay from IBM Rational Application Security
    for reporting an input validation error when processing SWF files
    (CVE-2009-0519).</li>
    <li>Javier Vicente Vallejo reported via the iDefense VCP that Adobe
    Flash does not remove object references properly, leading to a freed
    memory dereference (CVE-2009-0520).</li>
    <li>Josh Bressers of Red Hat and Tavis Ormandy of the Google Security
    Team reported an untrusted search path vulnerability
    (CVE-2009-0521).</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote attacker could entice a user to open a specially crafted SWF
    file, possibly resulting in the execution of arbitrary code with the
    privileges of the user or a Denial of Service (crash). Furthermore a
    remote attacker could gain access to sensitive information, disclose
    memory contents by enticing a user to open a specially crafted PDF file
    inside a Flash application, modify the victim's clipboard or render it
    temporarily unusable, persuade a user into uploading or downloading
    files, bypass security restrictions with the assistance of the user to
    gain access to camera and microphone, conduct Cross-Site Scripting and
    HTTP Header Splitting attacks, bypass the "non-root domain policy" of
    Flash, and gain escalated privileges.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Adobe Flash Player users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=www-plugins/adobe-flash-10.0.22.87"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-3873">CVE-2008-3873</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4401">CVE-2008-4401</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4503">CVE-2008-4503</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4818">CVE-2008-4818</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4819">CVE-2008-4819</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4821">CVE-2008-4821</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4822">CVE-2008-4822</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4823">CVE-2008-4823</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4824">CVE-2008-4824</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-5361">CVE-2008-5361</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-5362">CVE-2008-5362</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-5363">CVE-2008-5363</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-5499">CVE-2008-5499</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0114">CVE-2009-0114</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0519">CVE-2009-0519</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0520">CVE-2009-0520</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0521">CVE-2009-0521</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2009-03-09T11:37:22Z">
    a3li
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2009-03-09T12:37:48Z">
    p-y
  </metadata>
</glsa>
