<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200404-07">
  <title>ClamAV RAR Archive Remote Denial Of Service Vulnerability</title>
  <synopsis>
    ClamAV is vulnerable to a denial of service attack when processing certain
    RAR archives.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">clamav</product>
  <announced>2004-04-07</announced>
  <revised>2006-05-22: 02</revised>
  <bug>45357</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-antivirus/clamav" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.68.1</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">0.68</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    From <uri link="http://www.clamav.net/">http://www.clamav.net/</uri> :
    </p>
    <p>
    "Clam AntiVirus is a GPL anti-virus toolkit for UNIX. The main purpose
    of this software is the integration with mail servers (attachment
    scanning). The package provides a flexible and scalable multi-threaded
    daemon, a command line scanner, and a tool for automatic updating via
    Internet. The programs are based on a shared library distributed with
    the Clam AntiVirus package, which you can use with your own software.
    Most importantly, the virus database is kept up to date."
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Certain types of RAR archives, including those created by variants of
    the W32.Beagle.A@mm worm, may cause clamav to crash when it attempts to
    process them.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    This vulnerability causes a Denial of Service in the clamav process.
    Depending on	configuration, this may cause dependent services such as
    mail to fail as well.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    A workaround is not currently known for this issue. All users are
    advised to upgrade to the latest version of the affected package.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    ClamAV users should upgrade to version 0.68.1 or later:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    
    # emerge -pv "&gt;=app-antivirus/clamav-0.68.1"
    # emerge "&gt;=app-antivirus/clamav-0.68.1"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-1909">CVE-2004-1909</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    klieber
  </metadata>
</glsa>
