<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200505-20">
  <title>Mailutils: Multiple vulnerabilities in imap4d and mail</title>
  <synopsis>
    The imap4d server and the mail utility from GNU Mailutils contain multiple
    vulnerabilities, potentially allowing a remote attacker to execute
    arbitrary code with root privileges.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">mailutils</product>
  <announced>May 27, 2005</announced>
  <revised>May 27, 2005: 01</revised>
  <bug>94053</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-mail/mailutils" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.6-r1</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">0.6-r1</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    GNU Mailutils is a collection of mail-related utilities, including
    an IMAP4 server (imap4d) and a Mail User Agent (mail).
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    infamous41d discovered several vulnerabilities in GNU Mailutils.
    imap4d does not correctly implement formatted printing of command tags
    (CAN-2005-1523), fails to validate the range sequence of the "FETCH"
    command (CAN-2005-1522), and contains an integer overflow in the
    "fetch_io" routine (CAN-2005-1521). mail contains a buffer overflow in
    "header_get_field_name()" (CAN-2005-1520).
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    A remote attacker can exploit the format string and integer
    overflow in imap4d to execute arbitrary code as the imap4d user, which
    is usually root. By sending a specially crafted email message, a remote
    attacker could exploit the buffer overflow in the "mail" utility to
    execute arbitrary code with the rights of the user running mail.
    Finally, a remote attacker can also trigger a Denial of Service by
    sending a malicious FETCH command to an affected imap4d, causing
    excessive resource consumption.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There are no known workarounds at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All GNU Mailutils users should upgrade to the latest available
    version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose &quot;&gt;=net-mail/mailutils-0.6-r1&quot;</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2005-1520">CAN-2005-1520</uri>
    <uri link="http://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2005-1521">CAN-2005-1521</uri>
    <uri link="http://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2005-1522">CAN-2005-1522</uri>
    <uri link="http://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2005-1523">CAN-2005-1523</uri>
    <uri link="http://www.idefense.com/application/poi/display?type=vulnerabilities&amp;showYear=2005">iDEFENSE 05.25.05 advisories</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Thu, 26 May 2005 13:21:14 +0000">
    DerCorny
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="Fri, 27 May 2005 07:50:06 +0000">
    koon
  </metadata>
</glsa>
