<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200612-03">
  <title>GnuPG: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    GnuPG is vulnerable to a buffer overflow and an erroneous function pointer
    dereference that can result in the execution of arbitrary code.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">gnupg</product>
  <announced>2006-12-10</announced>
  <revised count="02">2006-12-10</revised>
  <bug>156476</bug>
  <bug>156947</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-crypt/gnupg" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.4.6</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">1.4.6</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    The GNU Privacy Guard, GnuPG, is a free replacement for the PGP suite
    of cryptographic software.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Hugh Warrington has reported a boundary error in GnuPG, in the
    "ask_outfile_name()" function from openfile.c: the
    make_printable_string() function could return a string longer than
    expected. Additionally, Tavis Ormandy of the Gentoo Security Team
    reported a design error in which a function pointer can be incorrectly
    dereferenced.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote attacker could entice a user to interactively use GnuPG on a
    crafted file and trigger the boundary error, which will result in a
    buffer overflow. They could also entice a user to process a signed or
    encrypted file with gpg or gpgv, possibly called through another
    application like a mail client, to trigger the dereference error. Both
    of these vulnerabilities would result in the execution of arbitrary
    code with the permissions of the user running GnuPG. gpg-agent, gpgsm
    and other tools are not affected.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All GnuPG users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "=app-crypt/gnupg-1.4*"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-6169">CVE-2006-6169</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-6235">CVE-2006-6235</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2006-12-07T11:29:58Z">
    jaervosz
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2006-12-08T11:06:22Z">
    falco
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2006-12-09T21:41:04Z">
    falco
  </metadata>
</glsa>
