<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<herd>mythtv</herd>
	<use>
		<flag name="alsa">Allows MythTV to directly output sound to ALSA devices,
		this is needed if you are using ALSA dmix or SPDIF. Note, you will have
		to physically type your device into the MythTV configuration since it
		will only give you /dev/dsp devices in the drop down.</flag>
		<flag name="altivec">Builds ffmpeg's codec libraries with altivec
		support.</flag>
		<flag name="autostart">Uses a custom autostart configuration gleaned from
		experience with MythTV since its early versions and discussed with
		other MythTV maintainers and users. Does not rely on KDE being installed
		like most methods do.</flag>
		<flag name="bluray">Pulls in libbluray for BluRay support.</flag>
		<flag name="cec">Allows you to control CEC enabled TVs via HDMI. Currently
		requires a USB based CEC -&gt; HDMI injector between your TV and video
		card since no graphics drivers support CEC natively.</flag>
		<flag name="crystalhd">Allows you to utilize a Broadcom CrystalHD hardware
		based video decoder to improve the performance of video decode.</flag>
		<flag name="debug">Instructs Qt to use the 'debug' target instead of
		'release' target. If your MythTV is crashing or you need a backtrace,
		you need to compile it with this option otherwise the debugging data is
		useless.</flag>
		<flag name="dvb">Enables support for Linux DVB cards. These include all
		cards that work with digital signals such as ATSC, DVB-T, DVB-C, and
		DVB-S, QAM-64, and QAM-256.</flag>
		<flag name="egl">Support EGL video output.</flag>
		<flag name="fftw">Support visualizations via <pkg>sci-libs/fftw</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="hls">HTTP Live Streaming support</flag>
		<flag name="ieee1394">Allows MythTV to communicate and use Firewire enabled
		Cable boxes. These are typically found in the United States, where such
		support is required by law. This will also install Firewire test
		programs and external channel changers if the internal changer does not
		work.</flag>
		<flag name="jack">Allows MythTV to use JACK as your sound output device. You
		will have to manually configure the path to your JACK settings.</flag>
		<flag name="lcd">Tells MythTV that you have an instance of
		<pkg>app-misc/lcdproc</pkg> configured on your machine and it should
		output information such as current time, show name, episode name, etc to
		that LCD.</flag>
		<flag name="lirc">Adds LIRC support directly to MythTV allowing for built in
		control via a LIRC device.</flag>
		<flag name="perl">Builds the perl bindings for MythTV. Allows you to write
		scripts in Perl to control your MythTV setup or communicate with
		it.</flag>
		<flag name="raop">Remote Audio Output Protocol (aka AirTunes/AirPlay)</flag>
		<flag name="xmltv">Pulls in the <pkg>media-tv/xmltv</pkg> TV listing
		grabbers for users not using Schedules Direct.</flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<remote-id type="github">MythTV/mythtv</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
