<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
<maintainer type="project">
	<email>games@gentoo.org</email>
	<name>Gentoo Games Project</name>
</maintainer>
<longdescription>
ThinkTanks is a tank combat game designed to be a blast for the new and 
experienced gamer alike with lighthearted, fast paced pandemonium. Either 
battling against brain-hungry bots in solo play or going head-to-head against 
others online, ThinkTanks has something for everyone.

You find yourself in a ThinkTank... just one of many brain slaves imprisoned by 
Alien Mind Control-- only you have managed to escape their brain rays. But the 
moment you are free, you are besieged on all sides by insane bot-tanks. You must 
destroy or be destroyed and keep on your toes at all times. Luckily you can 
collect powerups that give you wacky weapons to help you stay alive. As you 
progress through each level, the bot tanks get smarter, stronger and crazier as 
Alien Mind Control reprograms the bot tanks to match your wits. Your goal is to 
beat the bosses, then rescue your brain-brethren and continue the fight on other 
worlds.

Upon entering, you are immediately engaged by heavy artillery. This is 
no-holds-barred warfare and to the victor go the points. You can be catapulted or 
thrust in any direction by rolling over the boost and jump pads to escape attack 
or rush the enemy. The lush, green hills are scattered with bots on the warpath, 
bots choking in their own smoke, floating orbs with special powers and 
ammunition, boulders, trees, AND the dreaded pit of doom. The goal here is to 
keep your brain intact, and triumph over bots of every shape, size, speed and 
skill.

You are cast into a veritable feeding frenzy of tanks. You need to simultaneously 
track the position of your tank relative to the scrum ball using your radarscope, 
while navigating your tank along the bumpy terrain. If you are quick enough to 
pick up the ball yourself, you must make a mad dash to the goal, evading the 
thirsty pack of mad bots heavy on your trail. You win by capturing the most scrum 
balls in the allotted time.

Both On-line BattleMode and Scrum games have team-play variants and online chat 
that allow players to play together cooperatively.
</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
