<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>conikost@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Conrad Kostecki</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription>
		LCD4Linux is a small program that grabs information from the kernel
		and some subsystems and displays it on an external liquid crystal display.
	</longdescription>
	<use>
		<flag name="apm">Enable the APM plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="asterisk">Enable the Asterisk plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="button-exec">Enable the Button plugin, to execute something on keypress.</flag>
		<flag name="cpuinfo">Enable the cpuinfo plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="dbus">Enable the dbus plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="diskstats">Enable the diskstats plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="dmalloc">Enable dmalloc for debugging.</flag>
		<flag name="dvb">Enable support for the DVB plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="event">Enable the event plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="exec">Enable the exec plugin, to read output from external programs.</flag>
		<flag name="fifo">Enable the FIFO (First-In, First-Out) plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="file">Enable the file plugin, to read from input from files.</flag>
		<flag name="gps">Enable the gps plugin, for reading gps coordinates.</flag>
		<flag name="hddtemp">Enable the hddtemp plugin, to read from the hddtemp daemon.</flag>
		<flag name="huawei">Enable the huawei plugin, to read from a huawei device.</flag>
		<flag name="i2c-sensors">Enable the i2c_sensors plugin, to read sensor data.</flag>
		<flag name="iconv">Enable the iconv plugin, to convert between encodings.</flag>
		<flag name="isdn">Enable the isdn plugin, to get information about ISDN.</flag>
		<flag name="kvv">Enable the kvv plugin, to get realtime train schedule from the Karlsruher Verkehrsverbund.</flag>
		<flag name="loadavg">Enable the loadavg plugin, to get stats load</flag>
		<flag name="meminfo">Enable the meminfo plugin, to get memory statistics.</flag>
		<flag name="mpd">Enable the mpd plugin, to read from the Music Player Daemon.</flag>
		<flag name="mpris-dbus">Enable the mpris plugin, to read data via dbus for mpris.</flag>
		<flag name="mysql">Enable the mysql plugin, to get mysql database information.</flag>
		<flag name="netdev">Enable the netdev plugin, to get interface statistics.</flag>
		<flag name="netinfo">Enable the netinfo plugin, to get more interface statistic.</flag>
		<flag name="outb">Enable raw i/o access.</flag>
		<flag name="pop3">Enable the pop3 plugin, to get notified about new mails.</flag>
		<flag name="proc-stat">Enable the proc_stat plugin, to read data from the proc file system.</flag>
		<flag name="python">Enable support for <pkg>dev-lang/python</pkg> and enable the python plugin, to execute own python scripts.</flag>
		<flag name="qnaplog">Enable the qnaplog plugin, to read a log from a QNAP device.</flag>
		<flag name="raspi">Enable the raspi plugin, to read sensor data from a Raspberry Pi.</flag>
		<flag name="sample">Enable the sample plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="statfs">Enable the statfs plugin, to get statistics about the file system.</flag>
		<flag name="uname">Enable the uname plugin, to get the output of uname.</flag>
		<flag name="uptime">Enable the uptime plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="w1retap">Enable the w1retap plugin.</flag>
		<flag name="wireless">Enable the wireless plugin, to get wireless statistics.</flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<remote-id type="github">jmccrohan/lcd4linux</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
