<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer>
    <email>sound@gentoo.org</email>
  </maintainer>
  <longdescription lang="en">
    The purpose of beets is to get your music collection right once and for
    all. It catalogs your collection, automatically improving its metadata as
    it goes using the MusicBrainz database. (It also downloads cover art for
    albums it imports.) Then it provides a bouquet of tools for manipulating
    and accessing your music.

    Because beets is designed as a library, it can do almost anything you can
    imagine for your music collection. Via plugins, beets becomes a panacea:
    * Embed and extract album art from files’ tags.
    * Listen to your library with a music player that speaks the MPD protocol
    and works with a staggering variety of interfaces.
    * Fetch lyrics for all your songs from databases on the Web.
    * Manage your MusicBrainz music collection.
    * Analyze music files’ metadata from the command line.
    * Clean up crufty tags left behind by other, less-awesome tools.
    * Browse your music library graphically through a Web browser and play it
    in any browser that supports HTML5 Audio.

    If beets doesn’t do what you want yet, writing your own plugin is
    shockingly simple if you know a little Python.
  </longdescription>
  <use>
    <flag name="beatport">Enable support for beatport.com API</flag>
    <flag name="bpd">
      Enable support for <pkg>media-sound/mpd</pkg> server emulation
    </flag>
    <flag name="chroma">Enable support for acoustic fingerprinting plugin using
      <pkg>media-libs/chromaprint</pkg></flag>
    <flag name="convert">Enable support for the convert plugin which makes it
      possible to transcode files</flag>
    <flag name="discogs">Enable support for the discogs API plugin</flag>
    <flag name="echonest_tempo">Enable support for writing the BPM of a track
      into its metadata</flag>
    <flag name="echonest">Enable support for fetching and storing acoustic
      attributes of a track from Echo Nest</flag>
    <flag name="lastgenre">Enable support for importing music genres from
      last.fm tags</flag>
    <flag name="mpdstats">Enable support for collecting statistic about
      listening habits from <pkg>media-sound/mpd</pkg></flag>
    <flag name="opus">Enable opus support in gstreamer-based replaygain</flag>
    <flag name="replaygain">Enable support for Replay Gain metadata calculation
      during import</flag>
    <flag name="web">
      Enable embedded webserver support through <pkg>dev-python/flask</pkg>
    </flag>
  </use>
  <upstream>
    <remote-id type="pypi">beets</remote-id>
  </upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
