<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer type="project">
    <email>games@gentoo.org</email>
    <name>Gentoo Games Project</name>
  </maintainer>
  <longdescription>
Hello, and welcome to the Freedroid page.

THE CLASSICAL FREEDROID: Freedroid is a clone of the classic game
"Paradroid" on Commodore 64 with some improvements and extensions to
the classic version. 

In this game, you control a robot, depicted by a small white ball with
a few numbers within an interstellar spaceship consisting of several
decks connected by elevators. 

The aim of the game is to destroy all enemy robots, depicted by small
black balls with a few numbers, by either shooting them or seizing
control over them by creating connections in a short subgame of
electric circuits. 

Development of this game is now complete.  The final version came out
in august 2003 and runs on Linux, Mac OSX, Sharp Zaurus and even that
strange Windows wannabe of an operating system.  Thanks to all who 
helped.
Minor fixes and maintainance will of course still continue though...

FREEDROID RPG:  The Freedroid RPG is an extension/modification of the
classical freedroid engine into an RPG.  The main differences to the
classical version are as follows: 
* The Tux is the main character of the rpg.  He is not displayed as a
   ball like in Freedroid but rather as an animated character, while
   other droids and humans in the game are still represented as the balls
   with some number or code in them. 
* Dialogs and chatting with friendly droids and humans:
   Multiple-choice menus and voice samples (with subtitles for those
   without sound). 
* Melee weapons, armour and other items to be equipped have been
   added. 
* An automap feature was added.
* Saving and loading of games.
* A shop to trade things.
* Controls are different:  Mouse can be used to do everything.
   Joystick is not supported for moving around any more. 
* The archive size (including sound samples) is about 10 times as big
   as for the classical version.  I'd like to appologize to all 56K modem
   owners at this point. 
</longdescription>
  <upstream>
    <remote-id type="sourceforge">freedroid</remote-id>
  </upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
