<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer>
    <email>spiderx@spiderx.dp.ua</email>
    <name>Vladimir Pavljuchenkov</name>
    <description>Primary maintainer.</description>
  </maintainer>
  <herd>proxy-maintainers</herd>
  <longdescription>
    Stargazer is a powerful (inter)net billing system, capable of gathering
    traffic statistics from many sources (such as NetFlow protocol,
    ethernet packets capture, or IPQ subsystem), managing and billing user
    accounts according to specified fees and rules (including time-based rules,
    traffic source/destination rules and a payoff system).
    This ebuild allows you to compile it yourself depending of your needs.
  </longdescription>
  <use>
    <flag name="sgconv">Enable build of utility to convert Stargazer data between storage backends.</flag>
    <flag name="radius">Enable build of FreeRADIUS module for data access via Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="rscriptd">Enable build of remote script execute daemon for Stargazer, which run scripts when receive special signal from Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="sgauth">Enable build of command-line utility for authorization in Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="sgconf">Enable build of command-line utility for configuring Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="sgconf_xml">Enable build of command-line xml-based utility for configuring Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="stargazer">Enable build of Stargazer billing system.</flag>
    <flag name="debug">Enable extra debug codepaths, like asserts and extra output.</flag>
    <flag name="doc">Adds extra documentation (API, doc, etc).</flag>
    <flag name="examples">Install examples, usually source code.</flag>
    <flag name="static-libs">Install static libraries.</flag>
    <flag name="module_auth_always_online">Enable build of "Always Online" authentication module for Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="module_auth_internet_access">Enable build of "InetAccess" authentication module for Stargazer. InetAccess is a Stargazer specific authentication protocol.</flag>
    <flag name="module_auth_freeradius">Enable build of "Radius" authentication module for Stargazer. This module capable of using RADIUS procotol for user authentication.</flag>
    <flag name="module_capture_ether">Enable build of "Ethernet" traffic capture module for Stargazer. This module uses RAW sockets to capture traffic.</flag>
    <flag name="module_capture_ipq">Enable build of "IPQ" traffic capture module for Stargazer. This module uses IPQ subsystem to capture traffic.</flag>
    <flag name="module_capture_netflow">Enable build of "NetFlow" traffic capture module for Stargazer. This module capable of receiving traffic data by NetFlow protocol.</flag>
    <flag name="module_config_rpcconfig">Enable build of "XMLRPC" configuration module for Stargazer. This module uses XML-RPC protocol for configuring Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="module_config_sgconfig">Enable build of "SGConf" configuration module for Stargazer. This module uses Stargazer specific protocol for configuring Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="module_other_ping">Enable build of "Ping" module for Stargazer. This module pings connected users from time to time to ensure they are alive.</flag>
    <flag name="module_other_remote_script">Enable build of "Remote Script" module for Stargazer. This module control rscriptd daemon over the net and makes it execute scripts in reaction to different Stargazer events.</flag>
    <flag name="module_other_smux">Enable build of SMUX module for Stargazer. This module uses SMUX protocol to provide various information about Stargazer.</flag>
    <flag name="module_store_files">Enable build of storage plugin for Stargazer based on plain files.</flag>
    <flag name="module_store_firebird">Enable build of storage plugin for Stargazer, which uses Firebird database for storage.</flag>
    <flag name="module_store_mysql">Enable build of storage plugin for Stargazer, which uses MySQL for storage.</flag>
    <flag name="module_store_postgres">Enable build of storage plugin for Stargazer, which uses PostgreSQL for storage.</flag>
  </use>
  <upstream>
    <changelog>http://stg.dp.ua/server_dl.php</changelog>
    <doc>http://stg.dp.ua/doc.php</doc>
    <bugs-to>mailto:faust@stg.dp.ua</bugs-to>
  </upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
