<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person" proxied="yes">
		<email>waebbl-gentoo@posteo.net</email>
		<name>Bernd Waibel</name>
	</maintainer>
	<maintainer type="project" proxied="proxy">
		<email>proxy-maint@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Gentoo Proxy Maintainers</name>
	</maintainer>
	<use>
		<flag name="addonmgr">
			Build the addon manager module for automatic handling of 3rd 
			party addons
		</flag>
		<flag name="cloud">
			Build the Cloud workbench, to access cloud providers (mostly
			Amazon S3).
		</flag>
		<flag name="designer">
			Build and install the Qt designer plugin, so the FreeCAD widgets
			can be used from within designer.
		</flag>
		<flag name="drawing">
			Build the Drawing workbench, a predecessor to the TechDraw workbench.
			Users are encouraged to learn how to use the TechDraw workbench and
			switch to it instead.

			This is a compatibility option and will be removed in a later (0.20+)
			version of the package.
		</flag>
		<flag name="fem">
			Build the FEM module and workbench which provides Finite Element 
			Analysis (FEA) workflows
		</flag>
		<flag name="headless">
			Build FreeCAD without a GUI, usable for server-side instances.
			The Python modules are still available, without their GUI parts though.
		</flag>
		<flag name="idf">
			Build the IDF module to provide file exchange capabilities with
			IDF files
		</flag>
		<flag name="image">
			Build the image module and workbench for working with bitmap
			images
		</flag>
		<flag name="inspection">
			Build the inspection workbench which gives you specific tools
			for examination of shapes (experimental)
		</flag>
		<flag name="material">
			Build the material module and workbench to work with materials
		</flag>
		<flag name="openscad">
			Build the OpenSCAD module for interoperability with OpenSCAD 
			and repairing Constructive Solid Geometry (CSG) history
		</flag>
		<flag name="part-design">
			Build the part design module and workbench for build part shapes
			from sketches
		</flag>
		<flag name="path"><!-- FIXME: auto-enable through robot? -->
			Build the path module and workbench to procude G-Code instructions 
			for CNC
		</flag>
		<flag name="pcl">
			Use external <pkg>sci-libs/pcl</pkg> for point clouds support.
		</flag>
		<flag name="plot">
			Build the internal plot workbench. NOTE: This conflicts with the
			external plot workbench, which you can add via the Addon Manager!
		</flag>
		<flag name="points">
			Build the points module and workbench for working with point clouds
		</flag>
		<flag name="raytracing">
			Build the raytracing module and workbench for raytracing and rendering
		</flag>
		<flag name="robot">
			Build the robot module and workbench for studying robot movements
		</flag>
		<flag name="ship">
			Build the ship module and workbench which works over ship entities, 
			that must be created on top of provided geometry. NOTE: This conflicts
			with the external ship workbench, which you can add via the Addon Manager!
		</flag>
		<flag name="show">
			Build the show module, a helper module for visibility automation
		</flag>
		<flag name="surface">
			Build the surface module and workbench
		</flag>
		<flag name="techdraw">
			Build the techdraw module and workbench, a more advanced and 
			feature-rich successor of the drawing workbench
		</flag>
		<flag name="tux">
			Build the Tux module
		</flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<bugs-to>https://www.freecadweb.org/tracker/</bugs-to>
		<remote-id type="github">FreeCAD/FreeCAD</remote-id>
		<doc lang="en">https://www.freecadweb.org/wiki/MainPage</doc>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
