<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200403-08">
  <title>oftpd DoS vulnerability</title>
  <synopsis>
    A remotely-exploitable overflow exists in oftpd, allowing an attacker to
    crash the oftpd daemon.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">oftpd</product>
  <announced>2004-03-29</announced>
  <revised count="02">2006-05-22</revised>
  <bug>45738</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-ftp/oftpd" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.3.7</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">0.3.6</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Quote from <uri link="http://www.time-travellers.org/oftpd/">http://www.time-travellers
    .org/oftpd/</uri>
    </p>
    <p>
    "oftpd is designed to be as secure as an anonymous FTP server can
    possibly be. It runs as non-root for most of the time, and uses the
    Unix chroot() command to hide most of the systems directories from
    external users - they cannot change into them even if the server is
    totally compromised! It contains its own directory change code, so that
    it can run efficiently as a threaded server, and its own directory
    listing code (most FTP servers execute the system "ls" command to list
    files)."
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Issuing a port command with a number higher than 255 causes the server
    to crash. The port command may be issued before any authentication
    takes place, meaning the attacker does not need to know a valid
    username and password in order to exploit this vulnerability.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    This exploit causes a denial of service.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    While a workaround is not currently known for this issue, all users are
    advised to upgrade to the latest version of the affected package.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users should upgrade to the current version of the affected
    package:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    
    # emerge -pv "&gt;=net-ftp/oftpd-0.3.7"
    # emerge "&gt;=net-ftp/oftpd-0.3.7"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://www.time-travellers.org/oftpd/oftpd-dos.html">osftpd DoS Vulnerability</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-0376">CVE-2004-0376</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2006-05-22T05:52:22Z">
    DerCorny
  </metadata>
</glsa>
