<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200312-05">
  <title>GnuPG: ElGamal signing keys compromised and format string vulnerability</title>
  <synopsis>
    A bug in GnuPG allows ElGamal signing keys to be compromised, and a format
    string bug in the gpgkeys_hkp utility may allow arbitrary code execution.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">GnuPG</product>
  <announced>2003-12-12</announced>
  <revised>2003-12-12: 01</revised>
  <bug>34504</bug>
  <access>unknown</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-crypt/gnupg" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.2.3-r5</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">1.2.3-r4</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    GnuPG is a popular open source signing and encryption tool.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Two flaws have been found in GnuPG 1.2.3.
    </p>
    <p>
    First, ElGamal signing keys can be compromised.  These keys are not commonly
    used, but this is "a significant security failure which can lead to a
    compromise of almost all ElGamal keys used for signing.  Note that this is a
    real world vulnerability which will reveal your private key within a few
    seconds".
    </p>
    <p>
    Second, there is a format string flaw in the 'gpgkeys_hkp' utility which
    "would allow a malicious keyserver in the worst case to execute an arbitrary
    code on the user's machine."
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="minimal">
    <p>
    If you have used ElGamal keys for signing your private key can be
    compromised, and a malicious keyserver could remotely execute arbitrary code
    with the permissions of the user running gpgkeys_hkp.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users who have created ElGamal signing keys should immediately revoke
    them.  In addition, all Gentoo Linux machines with gnupg installed should be
    updated to use gnupg-1.2.3-r5 or higher:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    # emerge -pv '&gt;=app-crypt/gnupg-1.2.3-r5'
    # emerge '&gt;=app-crypt/gnupg-1.2.3-r5'
    # emerge clean</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2003-0971">CAN-2003-0971</uri>
    <uri link="http://marc.theaimsgroup.com/?l=gnupg-announce&amp;m=106992378510843&amp;q=raw">GnuPG Announcement</uri>
    <uri link="http://www.s-quadra.com/advisories/Adv-20031203.txt">S-Quadra Advisory</uri>
  </references>
</glsa>
