<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="201006-12">
  <title>Fetchmail: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been reported in Fetchmail, allowing remote
    attackers to execute arbitrary code or to conduct Man-in-the-Middle
    attacks.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">fetchmail</product>
  <announced>June 01, 2010</announced>
  <revised>June 01, 2010: 01</revised>
  <bug>280537</bug>
  <bug>307761</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-mail/fetchmail" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">6.3.14</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">6.3.14</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Fetchmail is a remote mail retrieval and forwarding utility.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been reported in Fetchmail:
    </p>
    <ul>
    <li>The sdump() function might trigger a heap-based buffer overflow
    during the escaping of non-printable characters with the high bit set
    from an X.509 certificate (CVE-2010-0562).</li>
    <li>The vendor reported
    that Fetchmail does not properly handle Common Name (CN) fields in
    X.509 certificates that contain an ASCII NUL character. Specifically,
    the processing of such fields is stopped at the first occurrence of a
    NUL character. This type of vulnerability was recently discovered by
    Dan Kaminsky and Moxie Marlinspike (CVE-2009-2666).</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote attacker could entice a user to connect with Fetchmail to a
    specially crafted SSL-enabled server in verbose mode, possibly
    resulting in the execution of arbitrary code with the privileges of the
    user running the application. NOTE: The issue is only existent on
    platforms on which char is signed.
    </p>
    <p>
    Furthermore, a remote attacker might employ a specially crafted X.509
    certificate, containing a NUL character in the Common Name field to
    conduct man-in-the-middle attacks on SSL connections made using
    Fetchmail.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Fetchmail users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose &quot;&gt;=net-mail/fetchmail-6.3.14&quot;</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-0562">CVE-2010-0562</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-2666">CVE-2009-2666</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="Mon, 29 Mar 2010 22:13:20 +0000">
    craig
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Sun, 11 Apr 2010 12:34:40 +0000">
    craig
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="Thu, 27 May 2010 17:49:00 +0000">
    vorlon
  </metadata>
</glsa>
