<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200406-07">
  <title>Subversion: Remote heap overflow</title>
  <synopsis>
    Subversion is vulnerable to a remote Denial of Service that may be
    exploitable to execute arbitrary code on the server running svnserve.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">dev-util/subversion</product>
  <announced>2004-06-10</announced>
  <revised>2004-06-10: 01</revised>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="dev-util/subversion" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.0.4-r1</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">1.0.4</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Subversion is a revision control system that aims to be a "compelling
    replacement for CVS". It enjoys wide use in the open source community.
    svnserve allows access to Subversion repositories using URIs with the
    svn://, svn+ssh://, and other tunelled svn+*:// protocols.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    The svn protocol parser trusts the indicated length of a URI string sent by
    a client. This allows a client to specify a very long string, thereby
    causing svnserve to allocate enough memory to hold that string. This may
    cause a Denial of Service. Alternately, given a string that causes an
    integer overflow in the variable holding the string length, the server
    might allocate less memory than required, allowing a heap overflow. This
    heap overflow may then be exploitable, allowing remote code execution. The
    attacker does not need read or write access to the Subversion repository
    being served, since even un-authenticated users can send svn protocol
    requests.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    Ranges from remote Denial of Service to potential arbitrary code execution
    with privileges of the svnserve process.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    Servers without svnserve running are not vulnerable. Disable svnserve and
    use DAV for access instead.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users should upgrade to the latest version of Subversion.
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv "&gt;=dev-util/subversion-1.0.4-r1"
    # emerge "&gt;=dev-util/subversion-1.0.4-r1"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0413">CAN-2004-0413</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    dmargoli
  </metadata>
</glsa>
