<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200408-08">
  <title>Cfengine: RSA Authentication Heap Corruption</title>
  <synopsis>
    Cfengine is vulnerable to a remote root exploit from clients in
    AllowConnectionsFrom.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">Cfengine</product>
  <announced>August 10, 2004</announced>
  <revised>May 22, 2006: 05</revised>
  <bug>59895</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-misc/cfengine" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">2.1.8</unaffected>
      <unaffected range="lt">2.0.0</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">2.1.7</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Cfengine is an agent/software robot and a high level policy language
    for building expert systems to administrate and configure large
    computer networks.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Two vulnerabilities have been found in cfservd. One is a buffer
    overflow in the AuthenticationDialogue function and the other is a
    failure to check the proper return value of the ReceiveTransaction
    function.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    An attacker could use the buffer overflow to execute arbitrary code
    with the permissions of the user running cfservd, which is usually the
    root user. However, before such an attack could be mounted, the
    IP-based ACL would have to be bypassed. With the second vulnerability,
    an attacker could cause a denial of service attack.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time. All users are encouraged to
    upgrade to the latest available version of Cfengine. (It should be
    noted that disabling cfservd will work around this particular problem.
    However, in many cases, doing so will cripple your Cfengine setup.
    Upgrading is strongly recommended.)
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Cfengine users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    
    # emerge -pv &quot;&gt;=net-misc/cfengine-2.1.8&quot;
    # emerge &quot;&gt;=net-misc/cfengine-2.1.8&quot;</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://www.coresecurity.com/common/showdoc.php?idx=387&amp;idxseccion=10">Corelabs Advisory</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-1701">CVE-2004-1701</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-1702">CVE-2004-1702</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Mon,  9 Aug 2004 21:29:04 +0000">
    jaervosz
  </metadata>
</glsa>
