<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200808-02">
  <title>Net-SNMP: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities in Net-SNMP allow for authentication bypass in
    snmpd and execution of arbitrary code in Perl applications using Net-SMNP.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">net-snmp</product>
  <announced>2008-08-06</announced>
  <revised>2008-08-06: 01</revised>
  <bug>222265</bug>
  <bug>225105</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-analyzer/net-snmp" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">5.4.1.1</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">5.4.1.1</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Net-SNMP is a collection of tools for generating and retrieving SNMP
    data. The SNMPv3 protocol uses a keyed-Hash Message Authentication Code
    (HMAC) to verify data integrity and authenticity of SNMP messages.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Wes Hardaker reported that the SNMPv3 HMAC verification relies on the
    client to specify the HMAC length (CVE-2008-0960). John Kortink
    reported a buffer overflow in the Perl bindings of Net-SNMP when
    processing the OCTETSTRING in an attribute value pair (AVP) received by
    an SNMP agent (CVE-2008-2292).
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    An attacker could send SNMPv3 packets to an instance of snmpd providing
    a valid user name and an HMAC length value of 1, and easily conduct
    brute-force attacks to bypass SNMP authentication. An attacker could
    further entice a user to connect to a malicious SNMP agent with an SNMP
    client using the Perl bindings, possibly resulting in the execution of
    arbitrary code.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Net-SNMP users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=net-analyzer/net-snmp-5.4.1.1"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-0960">CVE-2008-0960</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-2292">CVE-2008-2292</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2008-07-02T11:15:36Z">
    keytoaster
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2008-07-04T13:09:07Z">
    vorlon
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2008-07-07T08:46:03Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
</glsa>
