<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200407-21">
  <title>Samba: Multiple buffer overflows</title>
  <synopsis>
    Two buffer overflows vulnerabilities were found in Samba, potentially
    allowing the remote execution of arbitrary code.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">Samba</product>
  <announced>2004-07-29</announced>
  <revised>2004-07-29: 02</revised>
  <bug>57962</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-fs/samba" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">3.0.5</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">3.0.4-r1</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Samba is a package which allows *nix systems to act as file servers for
    Windows computers. It also allows *nix systems to mount shares exported by
    a Samba/CIFS/Windows server. The Samba Web Administration Tool (SWAT) is a
    web-based configuration tool part of the Samba package.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Evgeny Demidov found a buffer overflow in SWAT, located in the base64 data
    decoder used to handle HTTP basic authentication (CAN-2004-0600). The same
    flaw is present in the code used to handle the sambaMungedDial attribute
    value, when using the ldapsam passdb backend. Another buffer overflow was
    found in the code used to support the 'mangling method = hash' smb.conf
    option (CAN-2004-0686). Note that the default Samba value for this option
    is 'mangling method = hash2' which is not vulnerable.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    The SWAT authentication overflow could be exploited to execute arbitrary
    code with the rights of the Samba daemon process. The overflow in the
    sambaMungedDial handling code is not thought to be exploitable. The buffer
    overflow in 'mangling method = hash' code could also be used to execute
    arbitrary code on vulnerable configurations.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    Users disabling SWAT, not using ldapsam passdb backends and not using the
    'mangling method = hash' option are not vulnerable.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Samba users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv "&gt;=net-fs/samba-3.0.5"
    # emerge "&gt;=net-fs/samba-3.0.5"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://www.samba.org/samba/whatsnew/samba-3.0.5.html">Samba 3.0.5 Release Notes</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0600">CAN-2004-0600</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0686">CAN-2004-0686</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester">
    koon
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    koon
  </metadata>
</glsa>
