<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200808-12">
  <title>Postfix: Local privilege escalation vulnerability</title>
  <synopsis>
    Postfix incorrectly checks the ownership of a mailbox, allowing, in certain
    circumstances, to append data to arbitrary files on a local system with
    root privileges.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">postfix</product>
  <announced>August 14, 2008</announced>
  <revised>October 23, 2008: 02</revised>
  <bug>232642</bug>
  <access>local</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="mail-mta/postfix" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="rge">2.4.7-r1</unaffected>
      <unaffected range="ge">2.5.3-r1</unaffected>
      <unaffected range="rge">2.4.8</unaffected>
      <unaffected range="ge">2.4.9</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">2.5.3-r1</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Postfix is Wietse Venema's mailer that attempts to be fast, easy to
    administer, and secure, as an alternative to the widely-used Sendmail
    program.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Sebastian Krahmer of SuSE has found that Postfix allows to deliver mail
    to root-owned symlinks in an insecure manner under certain conditions.
    Normally, Postfix does not deliver mail to symlinks, except to
    root-owned symlinks, for compatibility with the systems using symlinks
    in /dev like Solaris. Furthermore, some systems like Linux allow to
    hardlink a symlink, while the POSIX.1-2001 standard requires that the
    symlink is followed. Depending on the write permissions and the
    delivery agent being used, this can lead to an arbitrary local file
    overwriting vulnerability (CVE-2008-2936). Furthermore, the Postfix
    delivery agent does not properly verify the ownership of a mailbox
    before delivering mail (CVE-2008-2937).
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    The combination of these features allows a local attacker to hardlink a
    root-owned symlink such that the newly created symlink would be
    root-owned and would point to a regular file (or another symlink) that
    would be written by the Postfix built-in local(8) or virtual(8)
    delivery agents, regardless the ownership of the final destination
    regular file. Depending on the write permissions of the spool mail
    directory, the delivery style, and the existence of a root mailbox,
    this could allow a local attacker to append a mail to an arbitrary file
    like /etc/passwd in order to gain root privileges.
    </p>
    <p>
    The default configuration of Gentoo Linux does not permit any kind of
    user privilege escalation.
    </p>
    <p>
    The second vulnerability (CVE-2008-2937) allows a local attacker,
    already having write permissions to the mail spool directory which is
    not the case on Gentoo by default, to create a previously nonexistent
    mailbox before Postfix creates it, allowing to read the mail of another
    user on the system.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    The following conditions should be met in order to be vulnerable to
    local privilege escalation.
    </p>
    <ul>
    <li>The mail delivery style is mailbox, with the Postfix built-in
    local(8) or virtual(8) delivery agents.</li>
    <li>The mail spool directory (/var/spool/mail) is user-writeable.</li>
    <li>The user can create hardlinks pointing to root-owned symlinks
    located in other directories.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
    Consequently, each one of the following workarounds is efficient.
    </p>
    <ul>
    <li>Verify that your /var/spool/mail directory is not writeable by a
    user. Normally on Gentoo, only the mail group has write access, and no
    end-user should be granted the mail group ownership.</li>
    <li>Prevent the local users from being able to create hardlinks
    pointing outside of the /var/spool/mail directory, e.g. with a
    dedicated partition.</li>
    <li>Use a non-builtin Postfix delivery agent, like procmail or
    maildrop.</li>
    <li>Use the maildir delivery style of Postfix ("home_mailbox=Maildir/"
    for example).</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
    Concerning the second vulnerability, check the write permissions of
    /var/spool/mail, or check that every Unix account already has a
    mailbox, by using Wietse Venema's Perl script available in the official
    advisory.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Postfix users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose &quot;&gt;=mail-mta/postfix-2.5.3-r1&quot;</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-2936">CVE-2008-2936</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-2937">CVE-2008-2937</uri>
    <uri link="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.mail.postfix.announce/110">Official Advisory</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Thu, 14 Aug 2008 13:13:26 +0000">
    falco
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="Thu, 14 Aug 2008 22:37:03 +0000">
    falco
  </metadata>
</glsa>
