<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200709-14">
  <title>ClamAV: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Vulnerabilities have been discovered in ClamAV allowing remote execution of
    arbitrary code and Denial of Service attacks.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">clamav</product>
  <announced>September 20, 2007</announced>
  <revised>September 20, 2007: 01</revised>
  <bug>189912</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-antivirus/clamav" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.91.2</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">0.91.2</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Clam AntiVirus is an open source (GPL) anti-virus toolkit for UNIX,
    designed especially for e-mail scanning on mail gateways.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Nikolaos Rangos discovered a vulnerability in ClamAV which exists
    because the recipient address extracted from email messages is not
    properly sanitized before being used in a call to "popen()" when
    executing sendmail (CVE-2007-4560). Also, NULL-pointer dereference
    errors exist within the "cli_scanrtf()" function in libclamav/rtf.c and
    Stefanos Stamatis discovered a NULL-pointer dereference vulnerability
    within the "cli_html_normalise()" function in libclamav/htmlnorm.c
    (CVE-2007-4510).
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    The unsanitized recipient address can be exploited to execute arbitrary
    code with the privileges of the clamav-milter process by sending an
    email with a specially crafted recipient address to the affected
    system. Also, the NULL-pointer dereference errors can be exploited to
    crash ClamAV. Successful exploitation of the latter vulnerability
    requires that clamav-milter is started with the "black hole" mode
    activated, which is not enabled by default.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All ClamAV users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose &quot;&gt;=app-antivirus/clamav-0.91.2&quot;</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-4510">CVE-2007-4510</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-4560">CVE-2007-4560</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Fri, 14 Sep 2007 22:57:24 +0000">
    mfleming
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="Sat, 15 Sep 2007 12:07:22 +0000">
    p-y
  </metadata>
</glsa>
