<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200912-01">
  <title>OpenSSL: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities in OpenSSL might allow remote attackers to conduct
    multiple attacks, including the injection of arbitrary data into encrypted
    byte streams.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">openssl</product>
  <announced>December 01, 2009</announced>
  <revised>December 02, 2009: 02</revised>
  <bug>270305</bug>
  <bug>280591</bug>
  <bug>292022</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="dev-libs/openssl" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.9.8l-r2</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">0.9.8l-r2</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    OpenSSL is an Open Source toolkit implementing the Secure Sockets Layer
    (SSL v2/v3) and Transport Layer Security (TLS v1) as well as a general
    purpose cryptography library.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been reported in OpenSSL:
    </p>
    <ul>
    <li>Marsh Ray of PhoneFactor and Martin Rex of SAP independently
    reported that the TLS protocol does not properly handle session
    renegotiation requests (CVE-2009-3555).</li>
    <li>The MD2 hash algorithm is no longer considered to be
    cryptographically strong, as demonstrated by Dan Kaminsky. Certificates
    using this algorithm are no longer accepted (CVE-2009-2409).</li>
    <li>Daniel Mentz and Robin Seggelmann reported the following
    vulnerabilities related to DTLS: A use-after-free flaw (CVE-2009-1379)
    and a NULL pointer dereference (CVE-2009-1387) in the
    dtls1_retrieve_buffered_fragment() function in src/d1_both.c, multiple
    memory leaks in the dtls1_process_out_of_seq_message() function in
    src/d1_both.c (CVE-2009-1378), and a processing error related to a
    large amount of DTLS records with a future epoch in the
    dtls1_buffer_record() function in ssl/d1_pkt.c
    (CVE-2009-1377).</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote unauthenticated attacker, acting as a Man in the Middle, could
    inject arbitrary plain text into a TLS session, possibly leading to the
    ability to send requests as if authenticated as the victim. A remote
    attacker could furthermore send specially crafted DTLS packages to a
    service using OpenSSL for DTLS support, possibly resulting in a Denial
    of Service. Also, a remote attacker might be able to create rogue
    certificates, facilitated by a MD2 collision. NOTE: The amount of
    computation needed for this attack is still very large.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All OpenSSL users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose &quot;&gt;=dev-libs/openssl-0.9.8l-r2&quot;</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1377">CVE-2009-1377</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1378">CVE-2009-1378</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1379">CVE-2009-1379</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1387">CVE-2009-1387</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-2409">CVE-2009-2409</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-3555">CVE-2009-3555</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="Mon, 23 Nov 2009 21:29:47 +0000">
    a3li
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Mon, 30 Nov 2009 13:42:39 +0000">
    a3li
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="Tue, 01 Dec 2009 21:28:40 +0000">
    a3li
  </metadata>
</glsa>
