<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200609-13">
  <title>gzip: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    gzip is affected by multiple vulnerabilities, including buffer overflows
    and infinite loops, possibly allowing the execution of arbitrary code.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">gzip</product>
  <announced>2006-09-23</announced>
  <revised count="01">2006-09-23</revised>
  <bug>145511</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-arch/gzip" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.3.5-r9</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">1.3.5-r9</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    gzip, the GNU zip compression utility, is a free and patent
    unencumbered replacement for the standard compress utility.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Tavis Ormandy of the Google Security Team has reported multiple
    vulnerabilities in gzip. A stack buffer modification vulnerability was
    discovered in the LZH decompression code, where a pathological data
    stream may result in the modification of stack data such as frame
    pointer, return address or saved registers. A static buffer underflow
    was discovered in the pack decompression support, allowing a specially
    crafted pack archive to underflow a .bss buffer. A static buffer
    overflow was uncovered in the LZH decompression code, allowing a data
    stream consisting of pathological huffman codes to overflow a .bss
    buffer. Multiple infinite loops were also uncovered in the LZH
    decompression code.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote attacker may create a specially crafted gzip archive, which
    when decompressed by a user or automated system exectues arbitrary code
    with the privileges of the user id invoking gzip. The infinite loops
    may be abused by an attacker to disrupt any automated systems invoking
    gzip to handle data decompression.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All gzip users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=app-arch/gzip-1.3.5-r9"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-4334">CVE-2006-4334</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-4335">CVE-2006-4335</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-4336">CVE-2006-4336</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-4337">CVE-2006-4337</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-4338">CVE-2006-4338</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2006-09-19T13:55:56Z">
    taviso
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2006-09-23T06:36:04Z">
    jaervosz
  </metadata>
</glsa>
