<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200404-20">
  <title>Multiple vulnerabilities in xine</title>
  <synopsis>
    Several vulnerabilities have been found in xine-ui and xine-lib,
    potentially allowing an attacker to overwrite files with the rights of the
    user.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">xine</product>
  <announced>April 27, 2004</announced>
  <revised>May 22, 2006: 02</revised>
  <bug>45448</bug>
  <bug>48107</bug>
  <bug>48108</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="media-video/xine-ui" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.9.23-r2</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">0.9.23-r1</vulnerable>
    </package>
    <package name="media-libs/xine-lib" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1_rc3-r3</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">1_rc3-r2</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    xine is a multimedia player allowing to play back CDs, DVDs, and VCDs
    and decoding multimedia files like AVI, MOV, WMV, and MP3 from local
    disk drives, and displays multimedia streamed over the Internet. It is
    available in Gentoo as a reusable library (xine-lib) with a standard
    user interface (xine-ui).
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Several vulnerabilities were found in xine-ui and xine-lib. By opening
    a malicious MRL in any xine-lib based media player, an attacker can
    write arbitrary content to an arbitrary file, only restricted by the
    permissions of the user running the application. By opening a malicious
    playlist in the xine-ui media player, an attacker can write arbitrary
    content to an arbitrary file, only restricted by the permissions of the
    user running xine-ui. Finally, a temporary file is created in an
    insecure manner by the xine-check and xine-bugreport scripts,
    potentially allowing a local attacker to use a symlink attack.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    These three vulnerabilities may alow an attacker to corrupt system
    files, thus potentially leading to a Denial of Service. It is also
    theoretically possible, though very unlikely, to use these
    vulnerabilities to elevate the privileges of the attacker.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time. All users are advised to
    upgrade to the latest available versions of xine-ui and xine-lib.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users of xine-ui or another xine-based player should upgrade to the
    latest stable versions:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    
    # emerge -pv &quot;&gt;=media-video/xine-ui-0.9.23-r2&quot;
    # emerge &quot;&gt;=media-video/xine-ui-0.9.23-r2&quot;
    
    # emerge -pv &quot;&gt;=media-libs/xine-lib-1_rc3-r3&quot;
    # emerge &quot;&gt;=media-libs/xine-lib-1_rc3-r3&quot;</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://xinehq.de/index.php/security">Xine Security Advisories</uri>
    <uri link="http://nettwerked.mg2.org/advisories/xinebug">xine-bugreport and xine-check vulnerability</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-0372">CVE-2004-0372</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-1951">CVE-2004-1951</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    koon
  </metadata>
</glsa>
