<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200410-11">
  <title>tiff: Buffer overflows in image decoding</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple heap-based overflows have been found in the tiff library image
    decoding routines, potentially allowing to execute arbitrary code with the
    rights of the user viewing a malicious image.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">tiff</product>
  <announced>October 13, 2004</announced>
  <revised>October 13, 2004: 01</revised>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="media-libs/tiff" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">3.6.1-r2</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">3.6.1-r2</vulnerable>
    </package>
    <package name="media-gfx/xv" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">3.10a-r8</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">3.10a-r7</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    The tiff library contains encoding and decoding routines for the Tag Image
    File Format. It is called by numerous programs, including GNOME and KDE, to
    help in displaying TIFF images. xv is a multi-format image manipulation
    utility that is statically linked to the tiff library.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Chris Evans found heap-based overflows in RLE decoding routines in
    tif_next.c, tif_thunder.c and potentially tif_luv.c.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A remote attacker could entice a user to view a carefully crafted TIFF
    image file, which would potentially lead to execution of arbitrary code
    with the rights of the user viewing the image. This affects any program
    that makes use of the tiff library, including GNOME and KDE web browsers or
    mail readers.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All tiff library users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv ">=media-libs/tiff-3.6.1-r2"
    # emerge ">=media-libs/tiff-3.6.1-r2"</code>
    <p>
    xv makes use of the tiff library and needs to be recompiled to receive the
    new patched version of the library. All xv users should also upgrade to the
    latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv ">=media-gfx/xv-3.10a-r8"
    # emerge ">=media-gfx/xv-3.10a-r8"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0803">CAN-2004-0803</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Mon, 11 Oct 2004 13:05:01 +0000">
    koon
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="Wed, 13 Oct 2004 14:38:12 +0000">
    koon
  </metadata>
</glsa>
