<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200801-09">
  <title>X.Org X server and Xfont library: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in the X.Org X server and
    Xfont library, allowing for a local privilege escalation and arbitrary code
    execution.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">xorg-server libXfont</product>
  <announced>2008-01-20</announced>
  <revised>2008-03-05: 03</revised>
  <bug>204362</bug>
  <bug>208343</bug>
  <access>remote, local</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="x11-base/xorg-server" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.3.0.0-r5</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">1.3.0.0-r5</vulnerable>
    </package>
    <package name="x11-libs/libXfont" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.3.1-r1</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">1.3.1-r1</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    The X Window System is a graphical windowing system based on a
    client/server model.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    regenrecht reported multiple vulnerabilities in various X server
    extension via iDefense:
    </p>
    <ul>
    <li>The XFree86-Misc extension does not properly sanitize a parameter
    within a PassMessage request, allowing the modification of a function
    pointer (CVE-2007-5760).</li>
    <li>Multiple functions in the XInput extension do not properly sanitize
    client requests for swapping bytes, leading to corruption of heap
    memory (CVE-2007-6427).</li>
    <li>Integer overflow vulnerabilities in the EVI extension and in the
    MIT-SHM extension can lead to buffer overflows (CVE-2007-6429).</li>
    <li>The TOG-CUP extension does not sanitize an index value in the
    ProcGetReservedColormapEntries() function, leading to arbitrary memory
    access (CVE-2007-6428).</li>
    <li>A buffer overflow was discovered in the Xfont library when
    processing PCF font files (CVE-2008-0006).</li>
    <li>The X server does not enforce restrictions when a user specifies a
    security policy file and attempts to open it (CVE-2007-5958).</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    Remote attackers could exploit the vulnerability in the Xfont library
    by enticing a user to load a specially crafted PCF font file resulting
    in the execution of arbitrary code with the privileges of the user
    running the X server, typically root. Local attackers could exploit
    this and the vulnerabilities in the X.org extensions to gain elevated
    privileges. If the X server allows connections from the network, these
    vulnerabilities could be exploited remotely. A local attacker could
    determine the existence of arbitrary files by exploiting the last
    vulnerability or possibly cause a Denial of Service.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    Workarounds for some of the vulnerabilities can be found in the X.Org
    security advisory as listed under References.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All X.Org X server users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=x11-base/xorg-server-1.3.0.0-r5"</code>
    <p>
    All X.Org Xfont library users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=x11-libs/libXfont-1.3.1-r1"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-5760">CVE-2007-5760</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-5958">CVE-2007-5958</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6427">CVE-2007-6427</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6428">CVE-2007-6428</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-6429">CVE-2007-6429</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-0006">CVE-2008-0006</uri>
    <uri link="https://lists.freedesktop.org/archives/xorg/2008-January/031918.html">X.Org security advisory</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2008-01-05T02:03:56Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2008-01-17T15:57:38Z">
    p-y
  </metadata>
</glsa>
