<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200702-08">
  <title>AMD64 x86 emulation Sun's J2SE Development Kit: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    Multiple unspecified vulnerabilities have been identified in Sun Java
    Development Kit (JDK) and Sun Java Runtime Environment (JRE).
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">java</product>
  <announced>2007-02-17</announced>
  <revised>2009-05-28: 02</revised>
  <bug>159547</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-emulation/emul-linux-x86-java" auto="yes" arch="amd64">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.5.0.10</unaffected>
      <unaffected range="rge">1.4.2.19</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">1.5.0.10</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    The Sun Java Development Kit (JDK) and the Sun Java Runtime Environment
    (JRE) provide the Sun Java platform. The x86 emulation Sun's J2SE
    Development Kit for AMD64 contains a vulnerable version of Sun's JDK.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Chris Evans has discovered multiple buffer overflows in Sun JDK and Sun
    JRE possibly related to various AWT or font layout functions. Tom
    Hawtin has discovered an unspecified vulnerability in Sun JDK and Sun
    JRE relating to unintended applet data access. He has also discovered
    multiple other unspecified vulnerabilities in Sun JDK and Sun JRE
    allowing unintended Java applet or application resource acquisition.
    Additionally, a memory corruption error has been found in the handling
    of GIF images with zero width field blocks.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    An attacker could entice a user to run a specially crafted Java applet
    or application that could read, write, or execute local files with the
    privileges of the user running the JVM, access data maintained in other
    Java applets, or escalate the privileges of the currently running Java
    applet or application allowing for unauthorized access to system
    resources.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All AMD64 x86 emulation Sun's J2SE Development Kit users should upgrade
    to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose "&gt;=app-emulation/emul-linux-x86-java-1.5.0.10"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-6731">CVE-2006-6731</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-6736">CVE-2006-6736</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-6737">CVE-2006-6737</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-6745">CVE-2006-6745</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-0243">CVE-2007-0243</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2007-02-12T22:34:40Z">
    falco
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2007-02-12T22:42:06Z">
    falco
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2007-02-12T22:57:40Z">
    falco
  </metadata>
</glsa>
