<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200407-20">
  <title>Subversion: Vulnerability in mod_authz_svn</title>
  <synopsis>
    Users with write access to parts of a Subversion repository may bypass read
    restrictions in mod_authz_svn and read any part of the repository they
    wish.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">subversion</product>
  <announced>2004-07-26</announced>
  <revised count="02">2006-05-22</revised>
  <bug>57747</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="dev-util/subversion" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">1.0.6</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">1.0.4-r1</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Subversion is an advanced version control system, similar to CVS, which
    supports additional functionality such as the ability to move, copy and
    delete files and directories. A Subversion server may be run as an
    Apache module, a standalone server (svnserve), or on-demand over ssh (a
    la CVS' ":ext:" protocol). The mod_authz_svn Apache module works with
    Subversion in Apache to limit access to parts of Subversion
    repositories based on policy set by the administrator.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Users with write access to part of a Subversion repository may bypass
    read restrictions on any part of that repository. This can be done
    using an "svn copy" command to copy the portion of a repository the
    user wishes to read into an area where they have write access.
    </p>
    <p>
    Since copies are versioned, any such copy attempts will be readily
    apparent.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="low">
    <p>
    This is a low-risk vulnerability. It affects only users of Subversion
    who are running servers inside Apache and using mod_authz_svn.
    Additionally, this vulnerability may be exploited only by users with
    write access to some portion of a repository.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    Keep sensitive content separated into different Subversion
    repositories, or disable the Apache Subversion server and use svnserve
    instead.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All Subversion users should upgrade to the latest available version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    
    # emerge -pv "&gt;=dev-util/subversion-1.0.6"
    # emerve "&gt;=dev-util/subversion-1.0.6"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://svn.collab.net/repos/svn/tags/1.0.6/CHANGES">ChangeLog for Subversion 1.0.6</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-1438">CVE-2004-1438</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester">
    koon
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    condordes
  </metadata>
</glsa>
