<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200612-11">
  <title>AMD64 x86 emulation base libraries: OpenSSL multiple vulnerabilities</title>
  <synopsis>
    OpenSSL contains multiple vulnerabilities including the possible execution
    of remote arbitrary code.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">emul-linux-x86-baselibs</product>
  <announced>December 11, 2006</announced>
  <revised>December 11, 2006: 01</revised>
  <bug>152640</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-emulation/emul-linux-x86-baselibs" auto="yes" arch="amd64">
      <unaffected range="ge">2.5.5</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">2.5.5</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    OpenSSL is a toolkit implementing the Secure Sockets Layer, Transport
    Layer Security protocols and a general-purpose cryptography library.
    The x86 emulation base libraries for AMD64 contain a vulnerable version
    of OpenSSL.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Tavis Ormandy and Will Drewry, both of the Google Security Team,
    discovered that the SSL_get_shared_ciphers() function contains a buffer
    overflow vulnerability, and that the SSLv2 client code contains a flaw
    leading to a crash. Additionally, Dr. Stephen N. Henson found that the
    ASN.1 handler contains two Denial of Service vulnerabilities: while
    parsing an invalid ASN.1 structure and while handling certain types of
    public key.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    An attacker could trigger the buffer overflow by sending a malicious
    suite of ciphers to an application using the vulnerable function, and
    thus execute arbitrary code with the rights of the user running the
    application. An attacker could also consume CPU and/or memory by
    exploiting the Denial of Service vulnerabilities. Finally, a malicious
    server could crash a SSLv2 client through the SSLv2 vulnerability.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All AMD64 x86 emulation base libraries users should upgrade to the
    latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --sync
    # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose &quot;&gt;=app-emulation/emul-linux-x86-baselibs-2.5.5&quot;</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-2937">CVE-2006-2937</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-2940">CVE-2006-2940</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-3738">CVE-2006-3738</uri>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-4343">CVE-2006-4343</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Tue, 24 Oct 2006 10:04:50 +0000">
    falco
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="Mon, 11 Dec 2006 23:29:14 +0000">
    falco
  </metadata>
</glsa>
