<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200410-03">
  <title>NetKit-telnetd: buffer overflows in telnet and telnetd</title>
  <synopsis>
    Buffer overflows exist in the telnet client and daemon provided by
    netkit-telnetd, which could possibly allow a remote attacker to gain root
    privileges and compromise the system.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">netkit-telnetd</product>
  <announced>2004-10-05</announced>
  <revised>2004-10-05: 01</revised>
  <bug>64632</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-misc/netkit-telnetd" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.17-r4</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="le">0.17-r3</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    NetKit-telnetd is a standard Linux telnet client and server from the NetKit
    utilities.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    A possible buffer overflow exists in the parsing of option strings by the
    telnet daemon, where proper bounds checking is not applied when writing to
    a buffer. Additionaly, another possible buffer overflow has been found by
    Josh Martin in the handling of the environment variable HOME.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    A remote attacker sending a specially-crafted options string to the telnet
    daemon could be able to run arbitrary code with the privileges of the user
    running the telnet daemon, usually root. Furthermore, an attacker could
    make use of an overlong HOME variable to cause a buffer overflow in the
    telnet client, potentially leading to the local execution of arbitrary
    code.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All NetKit-telnetd users should upgrade to the latest version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv "&gt;=net-misc/netkit-telnetd-0.17-r4"
    # emerge "&gt;=net-misc/netkit-telnetd-0.17-r4"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2001-0554">CVE-2001-0554</uri>
    <uri link="https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=264846">Debian Bug #264846</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2004-10-04T14:59:18Z">
    koon
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2004-10-04T16:13:52Z">
    vorlon078
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2004-10-05T14:10:00Z">
    vorlon078
  </metadata>
</glsa>
