<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200710-20">
  <title>PDFKit, ImageKits: Buffer overflow</title>
  <synopsis>
    PDFKit and ImageKits are vulnerable to an integer overflow and a stack
    overflow allowing for the user-assisted execution of arbitrary code.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">pdfkit imagekits</product>
  <announced>2007-10-18</announced>
  <revised>2007-10-18: 01</revised>
  <bug>188185</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="gnustep-libs/pdfkit" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <vulnerable range="le">0.9_pre062906</vulnerable>
    </package>
    <package name="gnustep-libs/imagekits" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <vulnerable range="le">0.6</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    PDFKit is a framework for rendering of PDF content in GNUstep
    applications. ImageKits is a collection of frameworks to support
    imaging in GNUstep applications.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Maurycy Prodeus discovered an integer overflow vulnerability possibly
    leading to a stack-based buffer overflow in the XPDF code which PDFKit
    is based on. ImageKits also contains a copy of PDFKit.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    By enticing a user to view a specially crafted PDF file with a viewer
    based on ImageKits or PDFKit such as Gentoo's ViewPDF, a remote
    attacker could cause an overflow, potentially resulting in the
    execution of arbitrary code with the privileges of the user running the
    application.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    PDFKit and ImageKits are not maintained upstream, so the packages were
    masked in Portage. We recommend that users unmerge PDFKit and
    ImageKits:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --unmerge gnustep-libs/pdfkit
    # emerge --unmerge gnustep-libs/imagekits</code>
    <p>
    As an alternative, users should upgrade their systems to use PopplerKit
    instead of PDFKit and Vindaloo instead of ViewPDF.
    </p>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-3387">CVE-2007-3387</uri>
    <uri link="https://www.gentoo.org/security/en/glsa/glsa-200709-12.xml">GLSA 200709-12</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2007-10-02T21:24:54Z">
    falco
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2007-10-07T23:31:24Z">
    rbu
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2007-10-09T18:28:10Z">
    p-y
  </metadata>
</glsa>
