<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200603-23">
  <title>NetHack, Slash'EM, Falcon's Eye: Local privilege escalation</title>
  <synopsis>
    NetHack, Slash'EM and Falcon's Eye are vulnerable to local privilege
    escalation vulnerabilities that could potentially allow the execution of
    arbitrary code as other users.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">nethack slashem falconseye</product>
  <announced>2006-03-23</announced>
  <revised>2006-03-30: 01</revised>
  <bug>125902</bug>
  <bug>122376</bug>
  <bug>127167</bug>
  <bug>127319</bug>
  <access>local</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="games-roguelike/nethack" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <vulnerable range="le">3.4.3-r1</vulnerable>
    </package>
    <package name="games-roguelike/falconseye" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <vulnerable range="le">1.9.4a</vulnerable>
    </package>
    <package name="games-roguelike/slashem" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <vulnerable range="le">0.0.760</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    NetHack is the classic single player dungeon exploration game. Slash'EM
    and Falcon's Eye are NetHack variants.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    NetHack, Slash'EM and Falcon's Eye have been found to be incompatible
    with the system used for managing games on Gentoo Linux. As a result,
    they cannot be played securely on systems with multiple users.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    A local user who is a member of group "games" may be able to modify the
    state data used by NetHack, Slash'EM or Falcon's Eye to trigger the
    execution of arbitrary code with the privileges of other players.
    Additionally, the games may create save game files in a manner not
    suitable for use on Gentoo Linux, potentially allowing a local user to
    create or overwrite files with the permissions of other players.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    Do not add untrusted users to the "games" group.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    NetHack has been masked in Portage pending the resolution of these
    issues. Vulnerable NetHack users are advised to uninstall the package
    until further notice.
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --ask --verbose --unmerge "games-roguelike/nethack"</code>
    <p>
    Slash'EM has been masked in Portage pending the resolution of these
    issues. Vulnerable Slash'EM users are advised to uninstall the package
    until further notice.
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --ask --verbose --unmerge "games-roguelike/slashem"</code>
    <p>
    Falcon's Eye has been masked in Portage pending the resolution of these
    issues. Vulnerable Falcon's Eye users are advised to uninstall the
    package until further notice.
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge --ask --verbose --unmerge "games-roguelike/falconseye"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-1390">CVE-2006-1390</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2006-03-22T22:13:28Z">
    DerCorny
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2006-03-22T22:57:23Z">
    taviso
  </metadata>
  <metadata tag="bugReady" timestamp="2006-03-23T22:05:55Z">
    jaervosz
  </metadata>
</glsa>
