<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">

<glsa id="200403-11">
  <title>Squid ACL [url_regex] bypass vulnerability</title>
  <synopsis>
    Squid versions 2.0 through to 2.5.STABLE4 could allow a remote attacker to
    bypass Access Control Lists by sending a specially-crafted URL request
    containing '%00': in such circumstances; the url_regex ACL may not properly
    detect the malicious URL, allowing the attacker to effectively bypass the
    ACL.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">Squid</product>
  <announced>March 30, 2004</announced>
  <revised>September 02, 2004: 02</revised>
  <bug>45273</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="net-proxy/squid" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">2.5.5</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">2.5.5</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    Squid is a fully-featured Web Proxy Cache designed to run on Unix systems
    that supports proxying and caching of HTTP, FTP, and other URLs, as well as
    SSL support, cache hierarchies, transparent caching, access control lists
    and many other features.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    A bug in Squid allows users to bypass certain access controls by passing a
    URL containing &quot;%00&quot; which exploits the Squid decoding function.
    This may insert a NUL character into decoded URLs, which may allow users to
    bypass url_regex access control lists that are enforced upon them.
    </p>
    <p>
    In such a scenario, Squid will insert a NUL character after
    the&quot;%00&quot; and it will make a comparison between the URL to the end
    of the NUL character rather than the contents after it: the comparison does
    not result in a match, and the user's request is not denied.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="normal">
    <p>
    Restricted users may be able to bypass url_regex access control lists that
    are enforced upon them which may cause unwanted network traffic as well as
    a route for other possible exploits. Users of Squid 2.5STABLE4 and below
    who require the url_regex features are recommended to upgrade to 2.5STABLE5
    to maintain the security of their infrastructure.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    A workaround is not currently known for this issue. All users are advised
    to upgrade to the latest version of Squid.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    Squid can be updated as follows:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv ">=net-proxy/squid-2.5.5"
    # emerge ">=net-proxy/squid-2.5.5"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0189">CAN-2004-0189</uri>
    <uri link="http://www.squid-cache.org/Advisories/SQUID-2004_1.txt">Squid 2.5.STABLE5 Release Announcement</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="Thu,  2 Sep 2004 21:11:59 +0000">
    vorlon078
  </metadata>
</glsa>
