<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200405-03">
  <title>ClamAV VirusEvent parameter vulnerability</title>
  <synopsis>
    With a specific configuration (using %f in the VirusEvent parameter), Clam
    AntiVirus is vulnerable to an attack allowing execution of arbitrary
    commands.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">ClamAV</product>
  <announced>2004-05-11</announced>
  <revised count="02">2006-05-22</revised>
  <bug>46264</bug>
  <access>remote</access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-antivirus/clamav" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="ge">0.70</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="lt">0.70</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    From <uri link="http://www.clamav.net/">http://www.clamav.net/</uri> :
    </p>
    <p>
    "Clam AntiVirus is a GPL anti-virus toolkit for UNIX. The main purpose
    of this software is the integration with mail servers (attachment
    scanning). The package provides a flexible and scalable multi-threaded
    daemon, a command line scanner, and a tool for automatic updating via
    Internet. The programs are based on a shared library distributed with
    the Clam AntiVirus package, which you can use with your own software.
    Most importantly, the virus database is kept up to date."
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    The VirusEvent parameter in the clamav.conf configuration file allows
    to specify a system command to run whenever a virus is found. This
    system command can make use of the "%f" parameter which is replaced by
    the name of the file infected. The name of the file scanned is under
    control of the attacker and is not sufficiently checked. Version 0.70
    of clamav disables the use of the "%f" parameter.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    Sending a virus with a malicious file name can result in execution of
    arbirary system commands with the rights of the antivirus process.
    Since clamav is often associated to mail servers for email scanning,
    this attack can be used remotely.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    You should not use the "%f" parameter in your VirusEvent configuration.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users of Clam AntiVirus should upgrade to the latest stable
    version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync
    
    # emerge -pv "&gt;=app-antivirus/clamav-0.70"
    # emerge "&gt;=app-antivirus/clamav-0.70"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2004-1876">CVE-2004-1876</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    koon
  </metadata>
</glsa>
