<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="200405-02">
  <title>Multiple vulnerabilities in LHa</title>
  <synopsis>
    Two stack-based buffer overflows and two directory traversal problems have
    been found in LHa. These vulnerabilities can be used to execute arbitrary
    code or as a denial of service attack.
  </synopsis>
  <product type="ebuild">lha</product>
  <announced>2004-05-09</announced>
  <revised>2006-10-20: 02</revised>
  <bug>49961</bug>
  <access>remote </access>
  <affected>
    <package name="app-arch/lha" auto="yes" arch="*">
      <unaffected range="rge">114i-r2</unaffected>
      <vulnerable range="rle">114i-r1</vulnerable>
    </package>
  </affected>
  <background>
    <p>
    LHa is a console-based program for packing and unpacking LHarc archives.
    </p>
  </background>
  <description>
    <p>
    Ulf Harnhammar found two stack overflows and two directory traversal
    vulnerabilities in LHa version 1.14 and 1.17. A stack overflow occurs when
    testing or extracting archives containing long file or directory names.
    Furthermore, LHa doesn't contain sufficient protection against relative or
    absolute archive paths.
    </p>
  </description>
  <impact type="high">
    <p>
    The stack overflows can be exploited to execute arbitrary code with the
    rights of the user testing or extracting the archive. The directory
    traversal vulnerabilities can be used to overwrite files in the filesystem
    with the rights of the user extracting the archive, potentially leading to
    denial of service or privilege escalation. Since LHa is often interfaced to
    other software like an email virus scanner, this attack can be used
    remotely.
    </p>
  </impact>
  <workaround>
    <p>
    There is no known workaround at this time. All users are advised to upgrade
    to the latest available version of LHa.
    </p>
  </workaround>
  <resolution>
    <p>
    All users of LHa should upgrade to the latest stable version:
    </p>
    <code>
    # emerge sync

    # emerge -pv "&gt;=app-arch/lha-114i-r2"
    # emerge "&gt;=app-arch/lha-114i-r2"</code>
  </resolution>
  <references>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0234">CAN-2004-0234</uri>
    <uri link="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2004-0235">CAN-2004-0235</uri>
  </references>
  <metadata tag="submitter">
    koon
  </metadata>
</glsa>
