<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<longdescription lang="en">
		Luanti (formerly Minetest) is a free software game engine to create various games
		based on voxel gameplay, inspired by InfiniMiner, Minecraft, and the like.
		Luanti was originally created by Perttu Ahola (alias “celeron55”).

		The basic idea of each game is always the same: The player is thrown into a huge world
		made out of cubes/blocks. Most of the time, these cubes make the landscape and these
		blocks can be removed and placed almost entirely freely. Using the collected items,
		new tools and other items can be crafted. Games in Luanti can, however, be much more
		complex than this.

		A core concept of Luanti is a built-in modding capability, based on the Lua programming language.
		Mods allow one or more certain aspects of an existing game to be modified. Luanti mods can be
		as simple as adding a few decoration blocks or very complex by (for example) introducing
		complex new gameplay concepts or generating a completely different kind of world, and many
		other things. For the player, using a new mod requires to copy or extract some files into
		a certain location and pressing some buttons in Luanti’s interface.

		Luanti can be played alone or online together with multiple players.

		Games for Luanti can be found on ContentDB.

		Features
		* A big cube-based world to discover (61840 nodes (cubes) in every dimension)
		* Procedurally generated world
		* Several world generators with many adjustable parameters
		* Extremely high configurability with an advanced settings editor and built-in descriptions,
			or by using a configuration file
		* Customize the graphics and sounds through texture packs
		* Download games, mods and texture packs from the built-in ContentDB
		* Singleplayer mode and online multiplayer mode
		* Server list
		* Sophisticated modding system using Lua
		* Mods are entirely server-sided. You can join any Luanti server with any mods and start playing,
			no additional software required
		* Relatively low system requirements
	</longdescription>
	<maintainer type="project">
		<email>games@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Gentoo Games Project</name>
	</maintainer>
	<use>
		<flag name="benchmark">Build with benchmarking support</flag>
		<flag name="client">Build Luanti client</flag>
		<flag name="curl">Enable use of online mod repo, public serverlist and remote media with <pkg>net-misc/curl</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="leveldb">Enable LevelDB map backend with <pkg>dev-libs/leveldb</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="ncurses">Enable server side ncurses terminal</flag>
		<flag name="openssl">Speed up SHA1 and SHA2 hashing with <pkg>dev-libs/openssl</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="postgres">Enable PostgreSQL map backend with <pkg>dev-db/postgresql</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="prometheus">Enable Prometheus client support</flag>
		<flag name="redis">Enable Redis map backend with <pkg>dev-libs/hiredis</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="server">Build Luanti server</flag>
		<flag name="spatial">Speed up AreaStores with <pkg>sci-libs/libspatialindex</pkg></flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<bugs-to>https://github.com/luanti-org/luanti/issues</bugs-to>
		<changelog>https://docs.luanti.org/about/changelog/</changelog>
		<doc>https://wiki.luanti.org/Main_Page</doc>
		<remote-id type="github">luanti-org/luanti</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
