<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>conikost@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Conrad Kostecki</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription>
		Cryptmount was written to make it as easy for ordinary users
		to access encrypted filesystems on-demand using the newer devmapper
		mechansism as it was to use the older, now deprecated, cryptoloop methods.
		This offers the following advantages:

		Access to improved functionality in the kernel
		Transparent support for filesystems stored on either raw disk partitions or loopback files
		Separate encryption of filesystem access keys, allowing access passwords to be changed without re-encrypting the entire filesystem
		Storing multiple encrypted filesystems within a single disk partition, using a designated subset of blocks for each
		Rarely used filesystems do not need to be mounted at system startup
		Un-mounting of each filesystem is locked so that this can only be performed by the user that mounted it, or the superuser
		Encrypted filesystems compatible with cryptsetup
		Encrypted access-keys can be chosen to be compatible with openssl, or managed via libgcrypt, or (for 2.0 release-series) built-in SHA1/Blowfish ciphers
		Support for encrypted swap partitions (superuser only)
		Support for setting up encrypted filesystems or crypto-swap at system boot-up
	</longdescription>
	<use>
		<flag name="argv0switch">Default action given by progname.</flag>
		<flag name="cswap">Enable support for encrypted swap.</flag>
		<flag name="fsck">Check filesystems before mounting.</flag>
		<flag name="gcrypt">Support libgcrypt-encryption of keys.</flag>
		<flag name="largefile">Enable support for large files.</flag>
		<flag name="mount">Use systemd mount/umount for operations.</flag>
		<flag name="luks">Enable key management via LUKS</flag>
		<flag name="openssl">Support openssl-encryption of keys.</flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<bugs-to>https://sourceforge.net/p/cryptmount/bugs/</bugs-to>
		<remote-id type="sourceforge">cryptmount</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
