<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
<maintainer type="project">
<email>netmon@gentoo.org</email>
<name>Gentoo network monitoring and analysis project</name>
</maintainer>
<longdescription>
(Note that version 3.80 is really 3.8, but released after 3.79.)

LFT, short for Layer Four Traceroute, is a sort of 'traceroute' that often
works much faster (than the commonly-used Van Jacobson method) and goes through
many configurations of packet-filters (firewalls). More importantly, LFT
implements numerous other features including AS number lookups through several
reliable sources, loose source routing, netblock name lookups, et al. What
makes LFT unique? LFT is the all-in-one traceroute tool because it can launch a
variety of different probes using ICMP, UDP, and TCP protocols, or the RFC1393
trace method. For example, rather than only launching UDP probes in an attempt
to elicit ICMP "TTL exceeded" from hosts in the path, LFT can send TCP SYN or
FIN probes to target arbitrary services. Then, LFT listens for "TTL exceeded"
messages, TCP RST (reset), and various other interesting heuristics from
firewalls or other gateways in the path. LFT also distinguishes between
TCP-based protocols (source and destination), which make its statistics
slightly more realistic, and gives a savvy user the ability to trace protocol
routes, not just layer-3 (IP) hops. With LFT's verbose output, much can be
discovered about a target network.

WhoB is a likable whois client (see whois(1)) designed to provide everything a
network engineer needs to know about a routed IP address by typing one line and
reading one line. But even so, it's worth typing a few more lines because WhoB
can do lots of other cool things for you! It can display the origin-ASN based
on the global routing table at that time (according to Prefix WhoIs, RIPE NCC,
or Cymru), the 'origin' ASN registered in the RADB (IRR), the netname and
orgname, etc. By querying pWhoIs, WhoB can even show you all prefixes being
announced by a specific Origin-ASN. WhoB performs the lookups quickly, the
output is easily parsed by automated programs, and it's included as part of the
Layer Four Traceroute (LFT) software package. LFT uses WhoB as a framework (and
you can too, quite easily--see whois.h). Recent LFT releases (as of version
2.5) include WhoB functionality through a standalone "whob" client/command
placed in the LFT binary directory. 

 LFT and WhoB continue to evolve and provide more and more useful data to
 network engineers and to anyone else that cares how IP datagrams are being
 routed. With the advent of smarter firewalls, traffic engineering, QoS, and
 per-protocol packet forwarding, LFT and WhoB have become invaluable tools for
 many network managers worldwide.
</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
