<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>mjo@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Michael Orlitzky</name>
	</maintainer>
	<maintainer type="project">
		<email>haskell@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Gentoo Haskell</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription>
		/Usage/:
		
		@
		list-remote-forwards [OPTIONS]
		@
		
		List all remote forwards for mail accounts stored in a SQL database.
		
		A list of local domains is supplied to the program (more or less)
		through the @--domain-query@ option. Any addresses which
		forward to another address not contained in this list of local domains
		is considered a remote forward. Remote forwards can cause problems for
		a number of reasons, the most common of which are,
		
		* If the sender has an SPF record authorizing his mail server to send
		mail on his behalf, then when his message is forwarded by the
		recipient's mail server, it will fail any subsequent SPF checks. This
		will likely cause the message to be rejected, and the original
		recipient's server will generate backscatter.
		
		* If any spam makes it through the filter on the recipient's mail
		server, that spam will then be forwarded to a remote destination. The
		remote destination will blame the forwarding server for the spam, and
		that can impact its reputation and potentially lead to a blacklisting
		even though the spam did not originate on the recipient's server.
		
		Whether or not these are an issue depends on the circumstances, but in
		any case it is useful to know who is forwarding mail off-site.
		
		/Input:/
		
		None.
		
		/Output:/
		
		A list of addresses that are forwarded to remote domains.
		
		/Options/:
		
		@
		\--database
		@
		
		The name of the database (or file, if SQLite) to which we should
		connect.
		
		Default: The name of the current user (Postgres only).
		
		@
		\--domain-query
		@
		SQL query used to produce a list of local domains. This should return
		the set of all domains (i.e one column) that are local to the
		server. See the default value for an example.
		
		Default: \"SELECT domain FROM domain WHERE domain &lt;&gt; 'ALL' ORDER BY domain;\"
		
		@
		\--exclude-mx, -e
		@
		
		The name of a mail exchanger, the forwards of whose domains we should
		ignore. For example, if one mail exchanger, mx1.example.com, has
		strict spam filtering, it may be acceptable to have remote forwarding
		for domains that have mx1.example.com as their sole mail exchanger (MX
		record). In that case, you might want to exclude those domains from
		the report by naming mx1.example.com here.
		
		A forward will be excluded from the report only if /all/ of its MX
		records are contained in the given exclude list.
		
		This option can be repeated to add mail exchangers to the exclude list.
		
		Default: [] (empty)
		
		@
		\--forward-query, -f
		@
		
		SQL query used to produce a list of all forwards on the mail
		system. This query should return the set of all (address, goto)
		triples, where \"goto\" is the destination address; i.e. to where
		the \"address\" forwards. The \"goto\" field may contain more
		than one email address, separated by commas.
		
		Default: \"SELECT address,goto FROM alias ORDER BY address;\"
		
		@
		\--host, -h
		@
		
		Hostname where the database is located (Postgres-only).
		
		Default: None, a UNIX domain socket connection is attempted (Postgres only)
		
		@
		\--password
		@
		
		Password used to connect to the database (Postgres-only).
		
		Default: None (assumes passwordless authentication)
		
		@
		\--port
		@
		Port number used to connect to the database (Postgres-only).
		
		Default: None, a UNIX domain socket connection is attempted (Postgres only)
		
		@
		\--username, -u
		@
		
		Username used to connect to the database (Postgres-only).
		
		Default: The current user
		
		/Examples/:
		
		@
		$ list-remote-forwards --database=test/fixtures/postfixadmin.sqlite3
		user1@example.com -&gt; user1@example.net
		user2@example.com -&gt; user1@example.org
		user2@example.com -&gt; user2@example.org
		user2@example.com -&gt; user3@example.org
		user7@example.com -&gt; user8@example.net
		@
	</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
