<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>slyfox@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Sergei Trofimovich</name>
		<description>Primary Maintainer</description>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription>
		It features a client-server model, allowing multiple (even simultaneous!) user
		interfaces, both textual and graphical. All common audio formats are supported
		using plugins. On top of this, there is a flexible media library to organize
		your music.

		List of features currently offered by XMMS2:
		  Client-server model:
		    * Allows XMMS2 to have various multiple interfaces (as clients).
			o Command line interfaces
			o GTK clients (matching GNOME &amp; XFCE4 look and feel)
			o KDE clients (matching KDE look and feel)
		    * Network transparency means you can run and control XMMS2 remotely, (e.g. run
		      XMMS2 on your 'media box' and control it over network using a bluetooth-enabled
		      PDA (TCP))
		  Wide format support:
		    * Can play FLAC, mp3, MOD, SID, speex, ogg vorbis, wave files.
		    * Clean separation of transport and decoder subsystems
		  Allows for more flexible access to media. (e.g. play mp3 files from a Samba
		  share without having to mount it on the local filesystem)
		Medialib:
		  Database-driven media library stores metadata about songs as they're played,
		  so songs can be quickly recalled and new playlists easily made.
	</longdescription>
	<use>
		<flag name="airplay">Support for airplay format</flag>
		<flag name="asf">Support for Monkey's Audio (APE) format with help of bundled libasf</flag>
		<flag name="gvfs">Transport for glibs virtual filesystem</flag>
		<flag name="ices">Icecast source output plugin</flag>
		<flag name="mac">Support for Monkey's Audio (APE) format with help of <pkg>media-sound/mac</pkg></flag>
		<flag name="ofa">Support for Open Fingerprint Architecture (OFA)</flag>
		<flag name="phonehome">This client sends anonymous usage-statistics to the xmms2</flag>
		<flag name="server">Build xmms2 player daemon (otherwise only clients are built)</flag>
		<flag name="sid">Support for C64 SID</flag>
		<flag name="vocoder">Phase vocoder effect plugin</flag>
		<flag name="mlib-update">Enable building of xmms2-mlib-updater client</flag>
		<flag name="xml">Enable support for various XML based playlists and sources: RSS, XSPF</flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<remote-id type="sourceforge">xmms2</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
