<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>marecki@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Marek Szuba</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription lang="en">
		The Platense Bible, also known as the Commented Bible, is a Catholic translation of the Bible into Spanish by the German Catholic priest Juan Straubinger. It is called Platense for having been done in the city of La Plata, Argentina. Publication Date: 1948. Textual basis: OT: Masoretic text, Nácar-Colunga and Bóver-Cantera bibles. Deuterocanonicals: Vulgate. NT: Textus Receptus, Merk critical edition.

		Msgr. Straubinger (1883-1956) was a German priest exiled in Argentina during World War II. Professor of Holy Scripture, theologian, exegete and Biblical scholastic. Author and translator of the Platense Bible, one of the most recognized versions of the Bible in Spanish. Straubinger's translation took very seriously many ancient and modern versions prior to his work, notably those of Nácar-Colunga (1944) and Bover-Cantera (1947).
	</longdescription>
	<longdescription lang="es">
		La Biblia Platense, también conocida como Biblia Comentada, es una traducción católica de la biblia al español realizada por el sacerdote católico alemán Juan Straubinger. Es llamada Platense por haberse hecho en la ciudad de La Plata, Argentina. Fecha de Publicación: 1948. Base textual: AT: texto masorético, biblias de Nácar-Colunga y Bóver-Cantera. Deuterocanónicos: Vulgata. NT: Textus Receptus, edición crítica de Merk.

		Mons. Straubinger (1883 — 1956) fue un sacerdote alemán exiliado en Argentina durante la II Guerra Mundial. Profesor de Sagrada Escritura, teólogo, exégeta y escolástico bíblico. Autor y traductor de la Biblia Platense, una de las más reconocidas versiones de la Biblia que hay en castellano. La traducción de Straubinger tomó muy seriamente en consideración numerosas versiones antiguas y modernas previas a sus trabajos, entre las que destacan las de Nácar-Colunga (1944) y Bover-Cantera (1947).
	</longdescription>
	<stabilize-allarches/>
</pkgmetadata>
