<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer>
		<email>pinkbyte@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Sergey Popov</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription>
		Quagga is a modern fork of Zebra. Quagga is a routing software package that provides TCP/IP
		based routing services with routing protocols support such as RIPv1, RIPv2, RIPng, OSPFv2,
		OSPFv3, BGP-4, and BGP-4+. Quagga also supports special BGP Route Reflector and Route Server
		behavior.  In addition to traditional IPv4 routing protocols, Quagga also supports IPv6 routing
		protocols. With SNMP daemon which supports SMUX protocol, Quagga provides routing protocol
		MIBs. Furthermore Quagga supports OSPFAPI, a API interface to the OSPF LSDB. It supports
		inspection as well as injection of normal and opaque OSPF LSAs. Applications like SRRD - The
		Service Rounting Redundancy Daemon - can make use of OSPFAPI to inject opaque data into the OSPF
		routing domain. SRRD, for example, implements a cluster server by using the OSPFAPI to flood
		service state information into the routing domain
	</longdescription>
	<use>
		<flag name="bgpclassless">
			Apply unofficial patch to enable classless prefixes for BGP. Patch and information to be found
			at http://hasso.linux.ee/doku.php/english:network:quagga
		</flag>
		<flag name="multipath">
			Enable multipath routes support for any number of routes
		</flag>
		<flag name="ospfapi">
			Enable OSPFAPI support for client applications accessing the OSPF link state database
		</flag>
		<flag name="tcp-zebra">
			Enable TCP zserv interface on port 2600 for Zebra/protocol-daemon communication. Unix domain
			sockets are chosen otherwise
		</flag>
		<flag name="readline">
			Enable support for <pkg>sys-libs/readline</pkg> to provide the Quagga Virtual Terminal
			Interface Shell (vtysh)
		</flag>
		<flag name="pam">
			Add support for PAM (via <pkg>sys-libs/pam</pkg>) to the Quagga Virtual Terminal Interface
			Shell (vtysh); if the readline USE flag is disabled, this flag is ignored
		</flag>
	</use>
</pkgmetadata>
