<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer type="project">
    <email>sysadmin@gentoo.org</email>
    <name>Gentoo Sysadmin Project</name>
  </maintainer>
  <longdescription lang="en">
    Munin the tool surveys all your computers and remembers what it saw. It
    presents all the information in in graphs through a web interface. Its
    emphasis is on plug and play capabilities. After completing a installation a
    high number of monitoring plugins will be playing with no more effort. Using
    Munin you can easily monitor the performance of your computers, networks,
    SANs, and quite possibly applications as well. It makes it easy to determine
    "what's different today" when a performance problem crops up. It makes it
    easy to see how you're doing capacity wise on all limited resources.
  </longdescription>
  <use>
    <flag name="mysql">
      Install the packages required for monitoring MySQL. Disabling
      the flag does not remove any plugin files.
    </flag>
    <flag name="postgres">
      Install the packages required for monitoring
      PostgreSQL. Disabling the flag does not remove any plugin files.
    </flag>
    <flag name="asterisk">
      Install the packages required for monitoring Asterisk. Disabling
      the flag does not remove any plugin files.
    </flag>
    <flag name="irc">
      Install the packages required for monitoring IRC. Disabling the
      flag does not remove any plugin files.
    </flag>
    <flag name="memcached">
      Install the packages required for memcached
      monitoring. Disabling the flag does not remove any plugin files.
    </flag>
    <flag name="ipmi">
      Install <pkg>sys-apps/ipmitool</pkg> required for monitoring
      IPMI sensors. Disabling the flag does not remove any plugin
      file.
    </flag>
    <flag name="http">
      Install <pkg>dev-perl/libwww-perl</pkg> required for monitoring
      HTTP-based services such as Apache and nginx. Disabling the flag
      does not remove any plugin file.
    </flag>
    <flag name="dhcpd">
      Install <pkg>dev-perl/Net-IP</pkg>,
      <pkg>dev-perl/HTTP-Date</pkg> and <pkg>net-misc/dhcp</pkg> to
      monitor DHCP lease usage. This only works if the server is on
      the same system as the node, so the server is also brought
      in. Disabling the flag does not remove any plugin file.
    </flag>
    <flag name="java">
      Build the Java-based plugins to monitor JMX-compatible
      applications. Disabling the flag removes the jmx monitoring
      plugins.
    </flag>
    <flag name="minimal">
      Only install munin-node and its plugins. This excludes the
      scripts to generate the web pages and the graphs.
    </flag>
    <flag name="cgi">
      Install the CGI-compatible scripts for on-the-fly generation of
      web pages and graphs. This is only meaningful if the minimal USE
      flag is disabled.
    </flag>
    <flag name="apache">
      Set up the configuration of the CGI generation of HTML and
      graphs to work with Apache. This also install an include-able
      configuration file.
    </flag>
    <flag name="ipv6">
      Add support for IPv6 in munin-node. IPv6 support for the master
      is always enabled, but the node requires a newer version of
    <pkg>dev-perl/net-server</pkg>, capable of listening to IPv6
      sockets.
    </flag>
    <flag name="syslog">
      Configure the node by default to log on syslog. This requires
      the presence of <pkg>virtual/perl-Sys-Syslog</pkg>. As of
      version 2.0.2, the master scripts only log to file, and not to
      syslog.
    </flag>
    <flag name="doc">
      Build and install a local copy of the HTML documentation for the
      whole software. This requires <pkg>dev-python/sphinx</pkg> to
      process the documentation sources.
    </flag>
  </use>
  <upstream>
    <remote-id type="sourceforge">munin</remote-id>
  </upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
