<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>bircoph@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Andrew Savchenko</name>
	</maintainer>
	<use>
		<flag name="X">Use the X window system</flag>
		<flag name="apidoc">Provide doxygen generated API docs</flag>
		<flag name="bzip2">Bzip2 loader support</flag>
		<flag name="filters">Build filter functions (blur, sharpen, etc)</flag>
		<flag name="gif">Gif image loader support</flag>
		<flag name="jpeg">Jpeg image loader support</flag>
		<flag name="heif">Heif and Avif image loader support</flag>
		<flag name="eps">Eps image loader support</flag>
		<flag name="jpegxl">Jxl image loader support</flag>
		<flag name="mp3">ID3 loader support</flag>
		<flag name="packing">Enable structure packing. This will reduce memory footprint at the cost of unaligned memory access</flag>
		<flag name="png">PNG image loader support</flag>
		<flag name="shm">Use MIT shared memory support for X image transfer</flag>
		<flag name="text">Build text (TrueType font) functions</flag>
		<flag name="tiff">TIFF image loader support</flag>
		<flag name="webp">WEBP image loader support</flag>
		<flag name="zlib">Zlib loader support</flag>
	</use>
	<longdescription>
		Imlib 2 is the successor to Imlib. It is not just a newer version - it
		is a completely new library. Imlib2 can be installed alongside Imlib
		1.x without any problems since they are effectively different libraries
		- but they Have very similar functionality.

		Imlib2 can do the following:
		* Load image files from disk in one of many formats,
		* Save images to disk in one of many formats,
		* Render image data onto other images,
		* Render images to an X-Windows drawable,
		* Produce pixmaps and pixmap masks of Images,
		* Apply filters to images,
		* Rotate images,
		* Accept RGBA Data for images,
		* Scale images,
		* Alpha blend Images on other images or drawables,
		* Apply color correction and modification tables and factors to
		images,
		* Render images onto images with color correction and modification
		tables,
		* Render truetype anti-aliased text,
		* Render truetype anti-aliased text at any angle,
		* Render anti-aliased lines,
		* Render rectangles,
		* Render linear multi-colored gradients,
		* Cache data intelligently for maximum performance,
		* Allocate colors automatically,
		* Allow full control over caching and color allocation,
		* Provide highly optimized MMX assembly for core routines,
		* Provide plug-in filter interface,
		* Provide on-the-fly runtime plug-in image loading and saving
		interface,
		* Fastest image compositing, rendering and manipulation library for X.

		If what you want isn't in the list above somewhere then likely Imlib 2
		does not do it. If it does it it likely does it faster than any other
		library you can find (this includes gdk-pixbuf, gdkrgb, etc.) primarily
		because of highly optimized code and a smart subsystem that does the
		dirty work for you and picks up the pieces for you so you can be lazy
		and let all the optimizations for you.

		Imlib 2 can run without a display, so it can be easily used for
		background image processing for web sites or servers - it only requires
		the X libraries to be installed - that is all - it does not require an
		XServer to run unless you wish to display images.
	</longdescription>
	<upstream>
		<remote-id type="sourceforge">enlightenment</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
