<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
<maintainer type="project">
	<email>games@gentoo.org</email>
	<name>Gentoo Games Project</name>
</maintainer>
<longdescription>
The Challenge Pro Mode (CPM) project was created by Richard 'Hoony' Sandlant in May 1999 
(when the 'Q3test' was released) after he realised that Quake 3 Arena was going to have a 
lot of "newbie-friendly" features and after John Carmack admitted a more challenging 
version might be better for professional gamers (which is where the name "pro mode" came 
from).

The Challenge Pro Mode's goals were, first and foremost, to make a more exciting and 
challenging game to play and we hoped that this would help advance Q3 into a professional 
sport. Along the way we made a choice between making only small conservative changes to 
Q3A, and making the changes that our design team recommended. We took the path of making 
the changes that our design team felt were necessary.

Our approach was to form an international project team and to separate "Design" from 
"Programming". While the programming team might have input into the design process they 
didn't make final design decisions - that was left to a team of experienced Quake players 
who tested changes using a "tweaks" mod. The design team consisted of players with a mix 
of competitive experience across Q1, Q2, Q3 and even UT.

Before the design team began their work we asked the community to 'brainstorm' a list 
(called the "candidates list") of all the possible changes they would like to see (some 
were contradictory). We also asked noted commentators (pundits) in the community what they 
thought might be best. The designers took note of all of these suggestions, and used a 
long process of tweaking and testing to develop the Challenge Pro Mode design. The team 
released two public betas of their work for feedback and input from the community.

And that is pretty much how the project team has worked ever since. The result is a 
gameplay design which we think is "finely tuned".
</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
