<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
<maintainer type="project">
  <email>emacs@gentoo.org</email>
  <name>Gentoo Emacs project</name>
</maintainer>
<longdescription>
  QEmacs (for Quick Emacs) is a very small but powerful text editor. It has
  the following features:
   * Full screen editor with an Emacs look and feel with all Emacs common
     features: multi-buffer, multi-window, command mode, universal argument,
     keyboard macros, config file with C like syntax, minibuffer with
     completion and history.
   * Can edit files of hundreds of megabytes quickly by using a highly
     optimized internal representation and by mmaping the file.
   * Full UTF8 support, including bidirectional editing respecting the Unicode
     bidi algorithm. Arabic and Indic scripts handling (in progress).
   * WYSIWYG HTML/XML/CSS2 mode graphical editing. Also supports lynx like
     rendering on VT100 terminals. WYSIWYG DocBook mode based on XML/CSS2
     renderer.
   * C mode: coloring with immediate update. Emacs like auto-indent.
   * Shell mode: colorized VT100 emulation so that your shell work exactly as
     you expect. You can run interactive terminal apps directly in the process
     buffer: mc, MenuConfig, or even qemacs itself! Compile mode with
     next/prev error.
   * Input methods for most languages, including Chinese (input methods come
     from the Yudit editor).
   * Hexadecimal editing mode with insertion and block commands. Unicode hexa
     editing of UTF8 files also supported.
   * Works on any VT100 terminals without termcap. UTF8 VT100 support included
     with double width glyphs.
   * X11 support. Support multiple proportionnal fonts at the same time (as
     XEmacs).
   * Small! Full version is about 150KB. Smaller custom versions can be built
     by removing modules.
</longdescription>
<upstream>
  <remote-id type="savannah-nongnu">qemacs</remote-id>
</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
