<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
<herd>games</herd>
<longdescription>
Loki, god of deception and mischief was the bane of the gods, a black sheep who
tormented all the heavens with his persistent schemes for personal power.
Asgard, the high heaven where the gods dwelt while determining the fates of man
and beast was often filled with the howls of pain and anguish as god after god
fell victim to one of Loki's plots. Having one day taken these malicious schemes
against his Asgardian brethren too far for a final time, Loki, lord of lies, was
imprisoned by Odin the All Father and his, Thor, the god of thunder:

Loki was chained to a bleak promontory hundreds of miles below the surface of
the earth. A venomous snake of immense proportions was wound around the
stalactites above him. From the mouth of this fearsome reptile dripped a steady
supply of acidic venom. The torment was horrific. The steady drops would eat
away the exiled god's midriff right down to the backbone. In turn, his immortal
powers of healing would slowly re-issue the flesh, only to have it burned away
again. The snake was unfailing, as were Loki's immortal healing powers.

And the excruciating agony for Loki was unending.

As Thor chained him to the rock, Odin All Father proclaimed that Loki would
remain under the constant drip of the venom until the day of Ragnarok; when
gods, men and giants would enter into a final battle and all reality as it
existed would perish. Then, and only then, would Loki be freed from his torment.

In that distant climactic battle between the gods of heaven and the monsters who
dwelt deep in the earth, it was assumed that Loki would fulfill his fate and
take up sides against the Asgardians. Of course, Loki was the bane of fate, and
he had other plans.

Rune was ported to Linux by Loki Entertainment Software and is a commercial
game, requiring the original media for installation.
</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
