<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>mgorny@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Michał Górny</name>
	</maintainer>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>williamh@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>William Hubbs</name>
	</maintainer>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>wizardedit@gentoo.org</email>
		<name>Austin English</name>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription>Low Level Virtual Machine (LLVM) is:
   1. A compilation strategy designed to enable effective program optimization across the entire lifetime of a program. LLVM supports effective optimization at compile time, link-time (particularly interprocedural), run-time and offline (i.e., after software is installed), while remaining transparent to developers and maintaining compatibility with existing build scripts.
   2. A virtual instruction set - LLVM is a low-level object code representation that uses simple RISC-like instructions, but provides rich, language-independent, type information and dataflow (SSA) information about operands. This combination enables sophisticated transformations on object code, while remaining light-weight enough to be attached to the executable. This combination is key to allowing link-time, run-time, and offline transformations.
   3. A compiler infrastructure - LLVM is also a collection of source code that implements the language and compilation strategy. The primary components of the LLVM infrastructure are a GCC-based C and C++ front-end, a link-time optimization framework with a growing set of global and interprocedural analyses and transformations, static back-ends for many popular (and some obscure) architectures, a back-end which emits portable C code, and a Just-In-Time compilers for several architectures.
   4. LLVM does not imply things that you would expect from a high-level virtual machine. It does not require garbage collection or run-time code generation (In fact, LLVM makes a great static compiler!). Note that optional LLVM components can be used to build high-level virtual machines and other systems that need these services.</longdescription>
	<use>
		<flag name="clang">Build the clang C/C++ compiler</flag>
		<flag name="doc">Build and install the HTML documentation and regenerate the man pages</flag>
		<flag name="gold">Build the gold linker plugin</flag>
		<flag name="lldb">Build the lldb debugger</flag>
		<flag name="multitarget">Build all host targets (default: host only)</flag>
		<flag name="ncurses">Support querying terminal properties using ncurses' terminfo</flag>
		<flag name="static-analyzer">Install the Clang static analyzer (requires USE=clang)</flag>
	</use>
</pkgmetadata>
