<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "https://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="project">
		<email>media-video@gentoo.org</email>
	</maintainer>
	<use>
		<flag name="bluray">
			Enable playback of Blu-ray filesystems using <pkg>media-libs/libbluray</pkg>
		</flag>
		<flag name="dav1d">
			Enable support for <pkg>media-libs/dav1d</pkg> AV1 decoder
		</flag>
		<flag name="dxr3">
			Enable support for DXR3 mpeg acceleration cards.
		</flag>
		<flag name="flac">
			Build the <pkg>media-libs/flac</pkg> based FLAC demuxer and decoder. This
			flag is not needed for playing FLAC content, neither standalone nor in Ogg
			container (OggFLAC), but might have better support for exotic features like
			24-bit samples or 96kHz sample rates.
		</flag>
		<flag name="gtk">
			Build the gdkpixbuf-based image decoder plugin.
		</flag>
		<flag name="imagemagick">
			Build the ImageMagick-based image decoder plugin.
		</flag>
		<flag name="mad">
			Build the <pkg>media-libs/libmad</pkg> based mp3 decoder. This mp3 decoder
			has superior support compared to the one coming from FFmpeg that is used as
			a fallback. If you experience any bad behaviour with mp3 files (skipping,
			distorted sound) make sure you enabled this USE flag.
		</flag>
		<flag name="mmap">
			Use mmap() function while reading file from local disks. Using mmap() will
			use more virtual memory space, but leaves to the Kernel the task of caching
			the file's data. mmap() access should be faster, but might misbehave if the
			device where the file resides in is removed during playback.
		</flag>
		<flag name="nfs">
			Allow accessing NFS shares via <pkg>net-fs/libnfs</pkg>.
		</flag>
		<flag name="truetype">
			Use <pkg>media-libs/freetype</pkg> for font rendering and
			<pkg>media-libs/fontconfig</pkg> for font discovery. Enabling this USE flag
			will allow OSD (such as subtitles) to use more advanced font and to more
			easily select which font to use. The support for TrueType fonts in xine-lib
			is still experimental, and might not be as good looking as the bitmap fonts
			used with this USE flag disabled.
		</flag>
		<flag name="sftp">
			Use <pkg>net-libs/libssh2</pkg> to access SFTP servers.
		</flag>
		<flag name="vdr">
			Build the VDR plugin
		</flag>
		<flag name="vidix">
			Enable support for vidix video output.
		</flag>
		<flag name="vis">
			Adds support for SIMD optimizations for UltraSPARC processors.
		</flag>
		<flag name="vpx">
			Enable VP8 codec support via <pkg>media-libs/libvpx</pkg>.
		</flag>
		<flag name="xvmc">
			Enable support for XVideo Motion Compensation (accelerated mpeg playback).
		</flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<remote-id type="sourceforge">xine</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
