<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer type="person">
    <email>lssndrbarbieri@gmail.com</email>
    <name>Alessandro Barbieri</name>
  </maintainer>
  <maintainer type="project">
    <email>proxy-maint@gentoo.org</email>
    <name>Proxy Maintainers</name>
  </maintainer>
  <upstream>
    <maintainer>
      <email>dstewart@math.uiowa.edu</email>
      <name>David Stewart</name>
    </maintainer>
  </upstream>
  <longdescription lang="en">
The Meschach Library is a numerical library of C routines for performing
calculations on matrices and vectors. It is intended for solving systems of
linear equations (dense and sparse), solve least squares problems,
computing eigenvalues and eigenvectors, etc. We do not claim that it
contains every useful algorithm in numerical linear algebra, but it does
provide a basis on which more advanced algorithms can be built. The library
is for people who know something about the C programming language,
something of how to solve the numerical problem they are faced with but do
not want to have the hassle of building all the necessary routines from the
scratch. The library is not a loose collection of numerical routines but it
comprises a coherent system. The current version is enhanced with many
features comparing with previous versions. Since the memory requirements
are nontrivial for large problems we have paid more attention to
allocation/deallocation of memory.
  </longdescription>
  <use>
    <flag name="complex">incorporate complex functions.</flag>
    <flag name="double">double precision</flag>
    <flag name="float">single precision</flag>
    <flag name="munroll">unroll low level loops on matrices</flag>
    <flag name="old">build no longer supported functions</flag>
    <flag name="segmem">should be set if you are working with a machine or compiler that does not allow large arrays to be allocated. See README</flag>
    <flag name="sparse">incorporate sparse matrix functions</flag>
    <flag name="test">build test programs</flag>
    <flag name="unroll">unroll low level loops on vectors</flag>
  </use>
</pkgmetadata>
