<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer type="project">
    <email>toolchain@gentoo.org</email>
    <name>Gentoo Toolchain Project</name>
  </maintainer>
  <use>
    <flag name="awt">Useful only when building GCJ, this enables Abstract Window Toolkit
      (AWT) peer support on top of GTK+</flag>
    <flag name="cilk">Support the Cilk Plus language (C/C++ based languages for parallel programming)</flag>
    <flag name="d">Enable support for the D programming language</flag>
    <flag name="fixed-point">Enable fixed-point arithmetic support for MIPS targets 
      in gcc (Warning: significantly increases compile time!)</flag>
    <flag name="go">Build the GCC Go language frontend.</flag>
    <flag name="graphite">Add support for the framework for loop
      optimizations based on a polyhedral intermediate representation</flag>
    <flag name="jit">Enable libgccjit so other applications can embed gcc for Just-In-Time compilation.
      This will slow down the compiler a bit as it forces all of the toolchain to be shared libs.</flag>
    <flag name="libssp">Build SSP support into a dedicated library rather than use the
      code in the C library (DO NOT ENABLE THIS IF YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT IT DOES)</flag>
    <flag name="mpx">Enable support for Intel Memory Protection Extensions (MPX)</flag>
    <flag name="mudflap">Add support for mudflap, a pointer use checking library</flag>
    <flag name="nopie">Disable PIE support (NOT FOR GENERAL USE)</flag>
    <flag name="nossp">Disable SSP support (NOT FOR GENERAL USE)</flag>
    <flag name="objc">Build support for the Objective C code language</flag>
    <flag name="objc++">Build support for the Objective C++ language</flag>
    <flag name="objc-gc">Build support for the Objective C code language Garbage
      Collector</flag>
    <flag name="regression-test">Run the testsuite and install the results (requires FEATURES=test)</flag>
    <flag name="sanitize">Build support for various sanitizer functions (ASAN/TSAN/etc...)</flag>
    <flag name="ssp">Build packages with stack smashing protector on by default</flag>
    <flag name="vtv">Build support for virtual table verification (a C++ hardening feature)</flag>
  </use>
  <upstream>
    <remote-id type="cpe">cpe:/a:gnu:gcc</remote-id>
    <remote-id type="sourceforge">dgcc</remote-id>
  </upstream>
</pkgmetadata>
