<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
  <maintainer type="person">
    <email>polynomial-c@gentoo.org</email>
    <name>Lars Wendler</name>
  </maintainer>
  <maintainer type="person">
    <email>mgorny@gentoo.org</email>
    <name>Michał Górny</name>
  </maintainer>
  <longdescription lang="en">
		Lziprecover is a data recovery tool and decompressor for files in the lzip 
		compressed data format (.lz), able to repair slightly damaged files, 
		recover badly damaged files from two or more copies, extract data from 
		damaged files, decompress files and test integrity of files.
		The lzip file format is designed for long-term data archiving. It is clean, 
		provides very safe 4 factor integrity checking, and is backed by the 
		recovery capabilities of lziprecover.
		Lziprecover is able to recover or decompress files produced by any of the 
		compressors in the lzip family; lzip, plzip, minilzip/lzlib, clzip and 
		pdlzip.
		Lziprecover makes lzip files resistant to bit-flip (one of the most common 
		forms of data corruption), and can safely merge multiple damaged backup 
		copies.
		If the cause of file corruption is damaged media, the combination GNU 
		ddrescue + lziprecover is the best option for recovering data from multiple 
		damaged copies.
		If a file is too damaged for lziprecover to repair it, all the recoverable 
		data in all members of the file can be extracted with the '-D' option.
		Lziprecover is able to efficiently extract a range of bytes from a 
		multi-member file, because it only decompresses the members containing the 
		desired data.
		Lziprecover can print correct total file sizes and ratios even for 
		multi-member files.
		When recovering data, lziprecover takes as arguments the names of the 
		damaged files and writes zero or more recovered files depending on the 
		operation selected and whether the recovery succeeded or not. The damaged 
		files themselves are never modified.
		When decompressing or testing file integrity, lziprecover behaves like lzip 
		or lunzip.
		To give you an idea of its possibilities, when merging two copies, each of 
		them with one damaged area affecting 1 percent of the copy, the probability 
		of obtaining a correct file is about 98 percent. With three such copies the 
		probability rises to 99.97 percent. For large files (a few MB) with small 
		errors (one sector damaged per copy), the probability approaches 100 percent 
		even with only two copies.
		Lziprecover is not a replacement for regular backups, but a last line of 
		defense for the case where the backups are also damaged.
  </longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
